<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>darktable on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in darktable on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>astrophoto denoise</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/astrophoto-denoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/astrophoto-denoise/</guid>
      <description>Remove image noise while preserving structure.&#xA;This is accomplished by averaging each pixel with some surrounding pixels in the image. The weight of such a pixel in the averaging process depends on the similarity of its neighborhood with the neighborhood of the pixel being denoised. A patch with a defined size is used to measure that similarity.&#xA;As denoising is a resource-intensive process, it slows down pixelpipe processing significantly. Consider activating this module late in your workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>base curve</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/base-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/base-curve/</guid>
      <description>Simulate the in-camera JPEG by applying a characteristic base curve to the image.&#xA;darktable comes with a number of base curve presets that attempt to mimic the curves of various camera manufacturers. These presets are automatically applied according to the manufacturer ID found in the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data. Camera-specific base curve presets are also available for some camera models.&#xA;This module will be enabled by default if preferences &amp;gt; processing &amp;gt; auto-apply pixel workflow defaults is set to &amp;ldquo;display-referred&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bloom</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/bloom/</guid>
      <description>Create a soft bloom effect.&#xA;This module works by blurring the highlights and then blending the result with the original image.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, and is no longer recommended. Instead, use the tone equalizer module or the exposure module with a parametric mask.&#xA;🔗module controls size The spatial extent of the bloom effect. threshold The threshold for the brightness increase. strength The strength of the overlighting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blurs</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/blurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/blurs/</guid>
      <description>Simulate physically-accurate blurs in scene-referred RGB space.&#xA;🔗blur types Three types of blur are provided:&#xA;lens blur: Simulates a lens diaphragm with a configurable number of blades and blade curvature to create synthetic bokeh. motion blur: Simulates the effect of camera motion with a configurable path. gaussian blur: This is not really an optical blur but can be used for denoising or for creative effects using blend modes A diagram at the top of the module shows the shape of the blurring operator (known as the point spread function).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>censorize</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/censorize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/censorize/</guid>
      <description>Degrade parts of the image in an aesthetically pleasing way, in order to anonymize people/objects or hide body parts.&#xA;Censorize works in linear RGB color space to apply a physically-accurate gaussian blur and gaussian luminance noise.&#xA;Aside from anonymization, this module can also be used for a wide range of creative purposes, for example:&#xA;Combine a simple blur with a multiply blend mode to create a realistic bloom (Orton effect). Combine a simple blur with a subtract blending mode and low opacity to create an unsharp mask, similar to the sharpen module but in an RGB scene-referred space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chromatic aberrations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/chromatic-aberrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/chromatic-aberrations/</guid>
      <description>Correct chromatic aberrations.&#xA;In contrast to the raw chromatic aberrations module, this module does not require raw data as input.&#xA;🔗workflow To obtain the best result, you are advised to proceed as follows:&#xA;Attenuate the chromatic aberrations as much as possible in the lens correction module using the TCA sliders. Increase the strength slider in this module to better see its effect. Increase the radius until the chromatic aberrations disappear. If this is insufficient, try enabling the &amp;ldquo;very large chromatic aberrations&amp;rdquo; setting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color balance</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance/</guid>
      <description>A versatile tool for adjusting the image&amp;rsquo;s color balance.&#xA;This module can be used to revert parasitic color casts or to enhance the visual atmosphere of an image using color grading, a popular technique in the cinema industry. For scene-referred workflow, you should consider using the improved color balance rgb module instead.&#xA;🔗overview The color balance module allows you to shift colors selectively by luminance range (shadows, mid-tones, and highlights). It can do this using two different methods:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color balance rgb</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance-rgb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance-rgb/</guid>
      <description>An advanced module which brings color-grading tools from cinematography into the photographic scene-referred pipeline.&#xA;This module is not suitable for beginners with no prior knowledge of color theory, who might want to stick to the global chroma and global vibrance settings until they have a good understanding of the dimensions of color.&#xA;🔗introduction Color-grading is an important part of image editing. It can help to remove unwanted color casts and can also deliver a creative color twist that will add atmosphere to your images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color calibration</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-calibration/</guid>
      <description>A fully-featured color-space correction, white balance adjustment and channel mixer module.&#xA;This simple yet powerful module can be used in the following ways:&#xA;To adjust the white balance (chromatic adaptation), working in tandem with the white balance module. Here, the white balance module makes some initial adjustments (required for the demosaic module to work effectively), and the color calibration module then calculates a more perceptually-accurate white balance after the input color profile has been applied.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color contrast</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-contrast/</guid>
      <description>A simplified control for changing the contrast or separation of colors between the green/magenta and blue/yellow axes in Lab color space. Higher values increase color contrast, lower values decrease it.&#xA;🔗module controls green-magenta contrast Change the green-magenta color contrast. This is equivalent to raising or lowering the steepness of the a* curve in Lab. Lower values desaturate greens and magenta, while higher values increase their saturation. blue-yellow contrast Change the blue-yellow color contrast.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color correction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-correction/</guid>
      <description>Modify the global image saturation to give the image a tint or as an alternative method to split-tone the image.&#xA;Note: Use the color balance rgb module for color modifications.&#xA;🔗module controls color board For split toning move the white dot to the desired highlight tint and then select a tint for shadows with the dark spot. For a simple global tint set both spots to the same color. saturation Correct the global saturation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color equalizer (placeholder)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-equalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-equalizer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color look up table</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-look-up-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-look-up-table/</guid>
      <description>A generic color look up table implemented in Lab space.&#xA;The input to this module is a list of source and target points and the complete mapping is interpolated using splines. The resulting look up tables (LUTs) are editable by hand and can be created using the darktable-chart utility to match given input (such as hald-cluts and RAW/JPEG with in-camera processing pairs). See using darktable-chart for details.&#xA;🔗module controls color board The color board grid shows a list of colored patches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color mapping</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Transfer the look and feel of one image to another.&#xA;This module statistically analyses the color characteristics of a source and target image. The colors of the source image are then mapped to corresponding colors on the target image.&#xA;Two steps are required to use this module:&#xA;Open the source image in the darkroom view and acquire its color characteristics by pressing the “acquire as source” button. A set of color clusters is generated and displayed in the “source clusters” area.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>Recover color information in blown-out highlights.&#xA;Due to the nature of digital sensors, overexposed highlights lack valid color information. Most frequently they appear neutral white or exhibit some color cast, depending on what other image processing steps are involved. This module can be used to “heal” overexposed highlights by replacing their colors with better fitting ones. The module acts on pixels whose luminance exceeds a user-defined threshold. Replacement colors are taken from neighboring pixels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color zones</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-zones/</guid>
      <description>Selectively adjust the lightness, chroma and hue of pixels based on their current lightness, chroma and hue.&#xA;This module works in CIE LCh color space, which separates pixels into lightness, chroma and hue components. It allows you to manipulate the lightness, chroma and hue of targeted groups of pixels through the use of curves.&#xA;You first need to choose whether you wish to adjust (select) pixels based on their lightness, chroma or hue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>colorize</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/colorize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/colorize/</guid>
      <description>Add a solid layer of color to the image.&#xA;🔗module controls hue The hue of the color layer. saturation The saturation of shadow tones. lightness The lightness of the color layer. source mix Controls how the lightness of the input image is mixed with the color layer. Setting this to zero will result in a uniformly colored plane. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>composite (placeholder)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/composite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/composite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contrast equalizer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-equalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-equalizer/</guid>
      <description>Adjust luminance and chroma contrast in the wavelet domain.&#xA;This versatile module can be used to achieve a variety of effects, including bloom, denoise, clarity, and local contrast enhancement.&#xA;It works in the wavelet domain and its parameters can be tuned independently for each wavelet detail scale. The module operates in CIE LCh color space and so is able to treat luminosity and chromaticity independently.&#xA;A number of presets are provided, which should help you to understand the capabilities of the module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>crop</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop/</guid>
      <description>Crop an image using on-screen guides.&#xA;This module appears later in the pipeline than the deprecated crop and rotate module, meaning that the full image can remain available for source spots in the retouch module. For best results, you are advised to use the rotate and perspective module to perform rotation and perspective correction (if required), and then perform final creative cropping with this module.&#xA;Whenever this module is in focus, the full uncropped image will be shown, overlaid with crop handles and optional guiding lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable/</guid>
      <description>The darktable binary starts darktable with its GUI and full functionality. This is the standard way to use darktable.&#xA;darktable can called with the following command line parameters:&#xA;darktable [-d {all,act_on,cache,camctl,camsupport,common,control, dev,expose,fswatch,imageio,input,ioporder,lighttable,lua, masks,memory,nan,opencl,params,perf,pipe,print,pwstorage, signal,sql,tiling,undo,verbose}] [--d-signal &amp;lt;signal&amp;gt;] [--d-signal-act &amp;lt;all,raise,connect,disconnect,print-trace&amp;gt;] [--disable-pipecache] [&amp;lt;input file&amp;gt;|&amp;lt;image folder&amp;gt;] [--version] [--disable-opencl] [--configdir &amp;lt;user config directory&amp;gt;] [--library &amp;lt;library file&amp;gt;] [--datadir &amp;lt;data directory&amp;gt;] [--moduledir &amp;lt;module directory&amp;gt;] [--tmpdir &amp;lt;tmp directory&amp;gt;] [--cachedir &amp;lt;user cache directory&amp;gt;] [--localedir &amp;lt;locale directory&amp;gt;] [--luacmd &amp;lt;lua command&amp;gt;] [--noiseprofiles &amp;lt;noiseprofiles json file&amp;gt;] [--conf &amp;lt;key&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;value&amp;gt;] [-t &amp;lt;num openmp threads&amp;gt;] All parameters are optional.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>demosaic</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/demosaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/demosaic/</guid>
      <description>Control how raw files are demosaiced.&#xA;🔗bayer filters The sensor cells of a digital camera are not color-sensitive &amp;ndash; they are only able to record different levels of lightness. In order to obtain a color image, each cell is covered by a color filter (red, green or blue) that primarily passes light of that color. This means that each pixel of the raw image only contains information about a single color channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>denoise (profiled)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/denoise-profiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/denoise-profiled/</guid>
      <description>An easy to use and highly efficient denoise module, adapted to the individual noise profiles of a wide range of camera sensors.&#xA;One issue with a lot of denoising algorithms is that they assume that the variance of the noise is independent of the luminosity of the signal. By profiling the noise characteristics of a camera&amp;rsquo;s sensor at different ISO settings, the variance at different luminosities can be assessed, and the denoising algorithm can be adjusted to more evenly smooth out the noise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>developing monochrome images</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/monochrome/</guid>
      <description>Photography has a long history of producing monochrome images, and many still enjoy this aspect of photography. While there are some specialized/modified cameras with a truly monochrome sensor, most still use a regular camera to capture a color image and transform it into a monochrome image during post-processing.&#xA;There are two main approaches to this conversion:&#xA;A physical approach, where we attempt to simulate how a silver-based photographic film emulsion would react to the light captured at the scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>diffuse or sharpen</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/diffuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/diffuse/</guid>
      <description>Diffusion is a family of physical processes by which particles move and spread gradually with time, from a source that generates them. In image processing, diffusion mostly occurs in two places:&#xA;diffusion of photons through lens glass (blur) or humid air (hazing), diffusion of pigments in wet inks or watercolors. In both cases, diffusion makes the image less sharp by &amp;ldquo;leaking&amp;rdquo; particles and smoothing local variations.&#xA;The diffuse or sharpen module uses a generalized physical model to describe several kinds of diffusion, and can be used by image makers to either simulate or revert diffusion processes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dither or posterize</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/dither-or-posterize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/dither-or-posterize/</guid>
      <description>This module eliminates some of the banding artifacts that can result when darktable&amp;rsquo;s internal 32-bit floating point data is transferred into discrete 8-bit or 16-bit integer output format for display or export. It can also be used for creative posterization effects.&#xA;Although not an inherent problem in any of darktable&amp;rsquo;s modules, some operations may provoke banding if they produce a lightness gradient in the image. To mitigate possible artifacts you should consider activating dithering when using the vignetting or graduated density modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>enlarge canvas (placeholder)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/enlarge-canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/enlarge-canvas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>exposure</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/exposure/</guid>
      <description>Increase or decrease the overall brightness of an image.&#xA;This module has two modes of operation:&#xA;manual Set the exposure and black level manually automatic (RAW images only) Use an analysis of the image&amp;rsquo;s histogram to automatically set the exposure. Darktable automatically selects the exposure compensation that is required to shift the selected percentile to the selected target level (see definitions below). This mode is particularly useful for automatically altering a large number of images to have the same exposure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filemanager</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/filemanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/filemanager/</guid>
      <description>In the default mode images are displayed in a grid with an adjustable number of images per row.&#xA;🔗controls zoom The number of images in each row can be altered using the slider in the bottom panel, or by holding Ctrl while scrolling over the center view with your mouse. navigate You can navigate through the images using the arrow keys (←/→/↑/↓) or by scrolling with your mouse. Press the Home key to scroll to the top of the collection, the End key to scroll to the bottom, and PageUp/PageDown to scroll up/down by a page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filmic rgb</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/filmic-rgb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/filmic-rgb/</guid>
      <description>Remap the tonal range of an image by reproducing the tone and color response of classic film.&#xA;This module can be used either to expand or to contract the dynamic range of the scene to fit the dynamic range of the display. It protects colors and contrast in the mid-tones, recovers the shadows, and compresses bright highlights and dark shadows. Highlights will need extra care when details need to be preserved (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>framing</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/framing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/framing/</guid>
      <description>Generate a frame around the image.&#xA;The frame consists of a border (with a user-defined color) and a frame line within that border (with a second user-defined color). Various options are available to control the geometry and color of the frame.&#xA;🔗module controls border size The size of the frame as a percentage of the underlying full image. aspect The aspect ratio of the final module output (i.e. the underlying image plus the frame).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>graduated density</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/graduated-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/graduated-density/</guid>
      <description>Simulate a graduated density filter in order to correct exposure and color in a progressive manner.&#xA;A line is shown on screen allowing the position and rotation of the gradient to be modified with the mouse.&#xA;This module is known to provoke banding artifacts under certain conditions. You should consider activating the dither or posterize module to alleviate these issues.&#xA;🔗module controls density Set the density of the filter (EV). A low value underexposes slightly whereas a high value creates a strong filter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>grain</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/grain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/grain/</guid>
      <description>Simulate the grain of analog film. The grain is processed on the L channel of Lab color space.&#xA;🔗module controls coarseness The grain size, scaled to simulate an ISO number. strength The strength of the effect. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>haze removal</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/haze-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/haze-removal/</guid>
      <description>Automatically reduce the effect of dust and haze in the atmosphere. This module may also be employed more generally to give pictures a color boost specifically in low-contrast regions of the image.&#xA;Haze absorbs light from objects in the scene but it is also a source of diffuse background light. The haze removal module first estimates, for each image region, the amount of haze in the scene. It then removes the diffuse background light according to its local strength and recovers the original object light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>highlight reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highlight-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highlight-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>Attempt to reconstruct color information for pixels that are clipped in one or more RGB channel.&#xA;🔗clipping Clipping occurs when the amount of captured light exceeds either the capacity of a camera&amp;rsquo;s sensor to record that light (photosite saturation) or the capacity of the Raw file to store it (digital clipping). Once a pixel is clipped we can no longer know the precise brightness of that pixel &amp;ndash; only that it is equal to or greater than the maximum value that pixel can store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>highpass</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highpass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highpass/</guid>
      <description>A high pass filter.&#xA;This module is primarily intended to be used in combination with a blend mode. For example, try using the module with a blend mode of &amp;ldquo;soft light&amp;rdquo; for high pass sharpening.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can result in undesirable effects, and is no longer recommended. Instead, use the contrast equalizer module for fine sharpness or the local contrast module for general sharpness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hot pixels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/hot-pixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/hot-pixels/</guid>
      <description>Automatically detect and eliminate hot pixels.&#xA;Hot pixels are pixels which have failed to record a light level correctly. Detected hot pixels are replaced by an average of their neighbors.&#xA;🔗module controls threshold How strong a pixel&amp;rsquo;s value needs to deviate from that of its neighbors to be regarded as a hot pixel. strength The blending strength of the hot pixels with their surrounding. detect by 3 neighbours Extend the detection of hot pixels &amp;ndash; regard a pixel as hot if a minimum of only three (instead of four) neighbor pixels deviate by more than the threshold level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>input color profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/input-color-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/input-color-profile/</guid>
      <description>Define how darktable will interpret the colors of the image.&#xA;This module takes the color space used by the image source (e.g. camera, scanner) and converts the pixel encodings to a standardized working color space. This means that subsequent modules in the pipeline don&amp;rsquo;t need to be concerned with the specifics of the input device, and can work with and convert to/from a common working color space.&#xA;Where an image has been captured in a raw file, the input color profile module will normally apply either a standard or enhanced color matrix specific for that camera model, which will be used to map the colors into the working profile color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>introduction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/introduction/</guid>
      <description>This section is intended to provide you with a flavor of what darktable can do and offer a suggested end-to-end processing workflow. New users should start by working through this introduction and following the links provided for further details.&#xA;Please note that this is not an exhaustive guide and many useful topics are not covered. You are advised to read through the reference sections of this manual once you are familiar with the basics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lens correction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lens-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lens-correction/</guid>
      <description>Automatically correct for (or simulate) lens distortion, transverse chromatic aberrations (TCA) and vignetting.&#xA;You can choose to either use lens correction data embedded in your Raw file (where present/supported) or correction data provided by the external Lensfun library.&#xA;Additional controls are also provided for manual vignetting correction, in case the profiles for your lens are insufficient or missing.&#xA;Note that if TCA correction is enabled in this module, also using raw chromatic aberrations may cause artifacts from over-correction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>liquify</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/liquify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/liquify/</guid>
      <description>Move pixels around by applying freestyle distortions to parts of the image using points, lines and curves.&#xA;As you might want to use source data from any part of the image you will be shown the uncropped image (possibly with the cropping rectangle overlaid as a guide) while the module is active.&#xA;🔗nodes Each of liquify&amp;rsquo;s tools is based on nodes. A point consists of a single node and a line or curve consists of a sequence of linked nodes defining a path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>local contrast</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/local-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/local-contrast/</guid>
      <description>Enhance the image&amp;rsquo;s local contrast.&#xA;This is achieved using either a local laplacian (default) or unnormalized bilateral filter. Both modes work exclusively on the L channel from Lab. The local laplacian filter has been designed to be robust against unwanted halo effects and gradient reversals along edges.&#xA;🔗module controls mode Choice of local laplacian filter or bilateral grid. The following sections define the controls available for each of these modes. 🔗bilateral grid coarseness Adjust the coarseness of the details to be adjusted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lowlight vision</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowlight-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowlight-vision/</guid>
      <description>Simulate human lowlight vision. This module can also be used to perform a day-to-night conversion.&#xA;The idea is to calculate a scotopic vision image, which is perceived by the rods rather than the cones in the eyes under low light. Scotopic lightness is then mixed with photopic value (regular color image pixel) using some blending function. This module can also simulate the Purkinje effect by adding some blueness to the dark parts of the image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lowpass</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowpass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowpass/</guid>
      <description>Apply a low pass filter (for example, a Gaussian blur) to the image, while controlling the output contrast and saturation.&#xA;This module is primarily intended to be used in combination with a blend mode. For example, try using the local contrast mask preset with the overlay blend mode.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can produce undesirable effects, and is no longer recommended. Instead, use the contrast equalizer module for blurring or the tone equalizer module for dynamic range compression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUT 3D</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lut-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lut-3d/</guid>
      <description>Transform RGB values with a 3D LUT file.&#xA;A 3D LUT is a tridimensional table that is used to transform a given RGB value into another RGB value. It is normally used for film simulation and color grading.&#xA;This module accepts .cube, .3dl, .png (haldclut) and .gmz files. Uncompressed 3D LUT data is not saved in the database or the XMP file, but is instead saved to the 3D LUT file path inside the 3D LUT root folder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>module header</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/module-header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/module-header/</guid>
      <description>At the top of each processing module is the module header.&#xA;Click on the module name to expand the module and display the parameters that control its operation.&#xA;By default darktable will only allow one processing module to be expanded at a time &amp;ndash; if you click the header of another module, the previously-opened module&amp;rsquo;s controls are collapsed. If you want to expand more than one module, you may expand further modules by Shift+clicking on the header and all previously expanded modules will remain open.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>monochrome</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/monochrome/</guid>
      <description>Quickly convert an image to black &amp;amp; white using a variable color filter.&#xA;To use this module, first reduce the filter size (to concentrate its effect) and move it across the hue palette to find the best filter value for your desired image rendition. Then gradually expand the filter to include more hues and achieve more natural tonality.&#xA;Although this module is easy to use, better results can usually be obtained by using the film emulation presets in the color calibration module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>negadoctor</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/negadoctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/negadoctor/</guid>
      <description>Process scanned film negatives.&#xA;You can obtain an image of a negative using a film scanner, or by photographing it against a white light (e.g. a light table or computer monitor) or off-camera flash.&#xA;🔗preparation If the image of the negative was obtained using a digital camera, then in order to obtain accurate colors in the final image, you will need to take the following points into consideration:&#xA;When taking the photograph, adjust the exposure to fully utilise the entire dynamic range of your camera sensor &amp;ndash; i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>orientation</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/orientation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/orientation/</guid>
      <description>Rotate the image 90 degrees at a time or flip the image horizontally and/or vertically.&#xA;The module is enabled by default and the orientation (rotation) is automatically set based on the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data.&#xA;The orientation can also be set using the actions on selection module in the lighttable view.&#xA;🔗module controls transform Double click the label to reset to the default transformations rotate counter-clockwise Rotate the image 90 degrees counter-clockwise rotate clockwise Rotate the image 90 degrees clockwise flip horizontally Flip the image (mirror) horizontally flip vertically Flip the image (mirror) vertically show guides Tick the box to show guide overlays whenever the module is activated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>output color profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/output-color-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/output-color-profile/</guid>
      <description>Manage the output profile for export and the rendering intent to be used when mapping between color spaces.&#xA;darktable comes with pre-defined profiles sRGB, Adobe RGB, XYZ and linear RGB. You can provide additional profiles by placing them in $DARKTABLE/share/darktable/color/out and $HOME/.config/darktable/color/out (where $DARKTABLE is the darktable installation directory and $HOME is your home directory). Note that these color/out directories are not created by the darktable install; if you need to use one, you must create it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/overview/</guid>
      <description>Masks allow you to limit the effect of a module so that it only applies to certain parts of the image.&#xA;A mask can be regarded as a grayscale image where each pixel has a value between 0 and 1.0 (or between 0% and 100%). This value is the opacity and is used to determine how much a module affects each pixel.&#xA;The following sections explain how to construct masks in darktable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/overview/</guid>
      <description>Each processing module takes its input from the preceding module in the pixelpipe, performs its operation on the image data, and then hands the output to the next module in the pixelpipe.&#xA;A module&amp;rsquo;s output data can optionally be reprocessed (combined) with its input data before being handed to the next module. This additional processing step is called blending &amp;ndash; input and output data is reprocessed using algorithms called blending operators or blend modes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/overview/</guid>
      <description>Processing modules are organized and accessed via the right-hand panel in the darkroom:&#xA;Click on the icons at the top of this panel to reveal, from left to right,&#xA;quick access panel A customizable panel allowing quick access to commonly-used module controls. active modules A group containing the modules that are currently active in the pixelpipe. Right-click to show all modules that are present in the history stack within the active group, regardless of whether or not they are actually active.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/overview/</guid>
      <description>The darkroom view is where you develop your images. The center panel contains the image currently being edited.&#xA;🔗zoom Middle-click on the center panel cycle between &amp;ldquo;fit to screen&amp;rdquo;, 1:1 and 2:1 zoom.&#xA;Alternatively you can zoom between 1:1 and &amp;ldquo;fit to screen&amp;rdquo; by scrolling with your mouse. Scroll while holding the Ctrl key to extend the zoom range to between 2:1 and 1:10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/overview/</guid>
      <description>The lighttable view allows you to view and manage your image collection.&#xA;The centre view contains thumbnails of your images &amp;ndash; how they are displayed depends on which mode you are working in.&#xA;While the mouse is over an image thumbnail or images are selected, there are a number of actions you can perform with keyboard shortcuts:&#xA;F1, F2, F3, F4, F5 adds or removes a color label (red, yellow, green, blue, purple, respectively).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/overview/</guid>
      <description>Lua scripts can be used to define actions for darktable to perform when an event is triggered. One example might be calling an external application during file export in order to apply additional processing steps outside of darktable.&#xA;Lua is an independent project founded in 1993, providing a powerful, fast, lightweight, embeddable scripting language. Lua is widely used by many open source applications, in commercial programs, and for games programming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/map/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/map/overview/</guid>
      <description>The map view allows you to see where your geo-tagged images were taken, and to add location information to non-geo-tagged images.&#xA;The map view shows a world map with the images in the current collection pinned to their geo-tagged location (if available). This requires that images are tagged with location information. Some newer cameras, including smartphones, are already equipped with GPS receivers. Other cameras may need additional GPS hardware to do this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/overview/</guid>
      <description>The modules in this reference section are broken down into two distinct types:&#xA;processing modules Processing modules are used exclusively in the darkroom view. Each module performs a processing operation on the image before passing its output to the next module for further processing. Together this sequence of processing steps forms the pixelpipe. utility modules Utility modules may be used in any darktable view. They are not directly involved in processing the pixels of an image but perform other ancillary functions (managing image metadata and tags, editing history, modifying pixel pipeline order, snapshots and duplicates, image export etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/overview/</guid>
      <description>darktable comes with a number of user-configurable preferences. These can be adjusted in the preferences dialog, which can be reached by clicking the gear icon on the right of the top panel. Preferences are separated into tabs, each of which is described in more detail in the following sections.&#xA;When opened from within the lighttable or darkroom views, the appropriate tab will be loaded by default to allow you to modify that view&amp;rsquo;s settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/print/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/print/overview/</guid>
      <description>This view allows you to print your images. Because printing is not easy, there are many technical aspects to be taken into account.&#xA;After selecting an image in the lighttable view you can enter the print settings module to adjust printer settings and initiate printing.&#xA;This module supports the printer&amp;rsquo;s ICC profile, which is somewhat mandatory if you want to obtain a high quality print close to the image displayed on the screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/slideshow/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/slideshow/overview/</guid>
      <description>The slideshow view allows you to watch a slideshow of your current collection with the associated filtering rules and sort order applied.&#xA;To learn more about how to define the collection and filtering rules, see the section on collections. Select the sort criteria and sort order of the images in the top panel.&#xA;The next section provides more details on the usage of the slideshow view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/overview/</guid>
      <description>darktable employs a fully color managed workflow:&#xA;Input color specifications are taken from embedded or user-supplied ICC profiles or (in the case of raw files) from a library of camera-specific color matrices.&#xA;darktable automatically reads the display profile of your monitor (if properly configured) for accurate on-screen color rendition. Multiple-screen setups are fully supported as long as a system service like colord is in place and properly configured to inform darktable of the correct monitor profile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/overview/</guid>
      <description>darktable-chart is a tool for extracting luminance and color values from images of color reference cards such as IT8.7/1 charts. Its main purpose is to compare a source image (typically a largely unprocessed raw image) to a target image (typically a JPEG image created in-camera) and produce a darktable style that is able to use the luminance and color values of the source image to produce the target image. This style employs the tone curve module, the input color profile module, and the color look up table module for that purpose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/overview/</guid>
      <description>The tethering view allows you to capture images directly into darktable from a connected camera.&#xA;To use the tethering feature you first need to connect your camera to your PC using a USB cable. Your computer might ask to mount or view the connected camera. Do not mount or view the camera. If your camera is mounted or viewed automatically, you will need to “unmount/eject” the camera before darktable can access it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw black/white point</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-black-white-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-black-white-point/</guid>
      <description>Define camera-specific black and white points.&#xA;This module is activated automatically for all raw images. Default settings are applied for all supported cameras. Changes to the defaults are not normally required.&#xA;🔗module controls black level 0-3 The camera-specific black level of the four pixels in the RGGB Bayer pattern. Pixels with values lower than this level are not considered to contain valid data. white point The camera-specific white level. All pixels with values above this are likely to be clipped and will be handled accordingly in the highlight reconstruction module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw chromatic aberrations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-chromatic-aberrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-chromatic-aberrations/</guid>
      <description>Correct chromatic aberrations of raw images.&#xA;This module currently only works for raw images recorded with a Bayer sensor (the sensor used in the majority of cameras) &amp;ndash; for other types of image, you should use the chromatic aberrations module instead.&#xA;The module will also not apply any corrections to any photos that have been identified as monochrome (see developing monochrome images for more information).&#xA;This module expects good white balance data (provided by the white balance module) for best results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw denoise</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-denoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-denoise/</guid>
      <description>Perform denoising on raw image data before it is demosaiced.&#xA;This module has been ported from dcraw.&#xA;🔗module controls noise threshold The threshold for noise detection. Higher values lead to stronger noise removal and greater loss of image detail. coarse/fine curves The noise of an image is usually a combination of fine-grained and coarse-grained noise. These curves allow the image to be denoised more or less depending on the coarseness of the visible noise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>retouch</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/retouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/retouch/</guid>
      <description>Remove unwanted elements from your image by cloning, healing, blurring and filling using drawn shapes.&#xA;This module extends the capabilities of the deprecated spot removal module (equivalent to this module&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;clone&amp;rdquo; tool) by including a &amp;ldquo;heal&amp;rdquo; tool (based on the heal tool from GIMP), as well as &amp;ldquo;fill&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;blur&amp;rdquo; modes. It can also take advantage of wavelet decomposition, allowing the image to be separated into layers of varying detail (from coarse to fine) which can be selectively retouched before being recombined to produce the output image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rgb curve</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-curve/</guid>
      <description>A classic digital photography tool to alter an image&amp;rsquo;s tones using curves.&#xA;This module is very similar to the tone curve module but works in RGB color space.&#xA;Activate the color picker on the left to show the picked values in the graph (Ctrl+click or right-click to use the picker in area mode). Numerical (Lab) values of the input and output (see below) at the selected spot or area are shown at the top left of the widget.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rgb levels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-levels/</guid>
      <description>Adjust black, white and mid-gray points in RGB color space. This module is silmilar to the levels module, which works in Lab color space.&#xA;The rgb levels tool shows a histogram of the image, and displays three bars with handles. Drag the handles to modify the black, middle-gray and white points in lightness (in &amp;ldquo;RGB, linked channels&amp;rdquo; mode) or independently for each of the R, G and B channels (in &amp;ldquo;RGB, independent channels&amp;rdquo; mode).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rgb primaries</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-primaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-primaries/</guid>
      <description>Adjust the hue and purity of the RGB primary colors (i.e. which red, green and blue they represent), while leaving uncolored (gray) pixels unchanged. In addition to preserving gray pixels, the opponency relationships between the colors are also preserved under this adjustment: If you increase the purity of the blue primary, the opponent yellow&amp;rsquo;s intensity increases to balance things out; If you twist the blue hue toward cyan, the opponent yellow is twisted toward orange.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rotate and perspective</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Automatically correct for converging lines, a form of perspective distortion. The underlying mechanism is inspired by Markus Hebel&amp;rsquo;s ShiftN program. This module also allows for the rotation of the image to be adjusted.&#xA;Perspective distortions are a natural effect when projecting a three dimensional scene onto a two dimensional plane and cause objects close to the viewer to appear larger than objects further away. Converging lines are a special case of perspective distortions frequently seen in architectural photographs &amp;ndash; parallel lines, when photographed at an angle, are transformed into converging lines that meet at some vantage point within or outside of the image frame.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rotate pixels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-pixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-pixels/</guid>
      <description>The sensors of some cameras (such as the Fujifilm FinePix S2Pro, F700, and E550) have a diagonally oriented Bayer pattern instead of the usual orthogonal layout.&#xA;Without correction this would lead to a tilted image with black corners. This module applies the required rotation.&#xA;darktable detects images that need correction using their Exif data and automatically activates this module where required. For other images the module always remains disabled.&#xA;The module has no controls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scale pixels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/scale-pixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/scale-pixels/</guid>
      <description>Some cameras (such as the Nikon D1X) have rectangular instead of the usual square sensor cells. Without correction this would lead to distorted images. This module applies the required scaling.&#xA;darktable detects images that need correction using their Exif data and automatically activates this module where required. For other images the module always remains disabled.&#xA;The module has no controls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shadows and highlights</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/shadows-and-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/shadows-and-highlights/</guid>
      <description>Modify the tonal range of the shadows and highlights of an image by enhancing local contrast.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can result in a number of issues when the parameters are pushed hard, including halos, high local contrast in highlights, and hue shifts towards blue in the shadows. You are advised to use the tone equalizer module instead.&#xA;🔗module controls shadows Control the effect on shadows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sharpen</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sharpen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sharpen/</guid>
      <description>Sharpen the details in the image using a standard UnSharp Mask (USM).&#xA;This module works by increasing the contrast around edges and thereby enhancing the impression of sharpness of an image. This module is applied to the L channel in Lab color space.&#xA;Note: The USM algorithm used in this module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can produce undesirable effects, and is no longer recommended. Instead use the presets offered by the contrast equalizer module for deblurring or the local contrast module for general sharpness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sidecar files</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/sidecar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/sidecar/</guid>
      <description>darktable is a non-destructive image editor and opens all images in read-only mode. Any data created within darktable (metadata, tags, and image processing steps) is stored in separate .XMP sidecar files. These files are stored alongside the original Raw files and allow darktable to store information about the images as well as the full editing history without touching the original raw files. When you import an image into darktable for the first time, an XMP file is automatically generated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sigmoid</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sigmoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sigmoid/</guid>
      <description>Remap the tonal range of an image using a modified generalized log-logistic curve.&#xA;This module can be used to expand or contract the dynamic range of the scene to fit the dynamic range of the display.&#xA;Note: Modules placed before sigmoid in the pipeline operate in scene-referred space. Modules after sigmoid work in display-referred space.&#xA;🔗usage Please take note of the following guidelines while using this module within your workflow:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>soften</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/soften/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/soften/</guid>
      <description>Create a softened image using the Orton effect.&#xA;Michael Orton achieved his results on slide film by using two exposures of the same scene, one well exposed and one overexposed. He then used a darkroom technique to blend these two images into a final image where the overexposed image was blurred.&#xA;This module is a near-copy of Orton&amp;rsquo;s analog process into the digital domain.&#xA;🔗module controls size The size of blur of the overexposed image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>split-toning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/split-toning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/split-toning/</guid>
      <description>Create a two color linear toning effect where the shadows and highlights are represented by two different colors.&#xA;The split-toning module does not convert images to black and white and has limited benefits on color images. In order to perform traditional split-toning, the input to this module should therefore be monochrome.&#xA;🔗module controls shadows and highlights color Set the desired hue and saturation for both shadows and highlights. Clicking on the colored squares will open a color selector dialog which offers you a choice of commonly used colors, or allows you to define a color in RGB color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>surface blur</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/surface-blur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/surface-blur/</guid>
      <description>Smooth image surfaces while preserving sharp edges using a bilateral filter.&#xA;This module can be used to denoise images, however you should be aware that bilateral filters are susceptible to overshoots and darktable offers much better alternatives. For example, the astrophoto denoise module uses a non-local means denoising algorithm, and the denoise (profiled) module provides a choice between non-local means and wavelet denoising algorithms.&#xA;The surface blur module blurs noise within the surfaces of an image by averaging pixels with their neighbors, taking into account not only their geometric distance but also their distance on the range scale (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the anatomy of a processing module</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/the-anatomy-of-a-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/the-anatomy-of-a-module/</guid>
      <description>The basic element of image processing in darktable is the processing module. In order to process a raw image a number of such modules act on the input image in sequence, each performing a different operation on the image data. For those familiar with Adobe Photoshop, the concept of a processing module in darktable is analogous to that of an adjustment layer in that both make an incremental adjustment to the image, building on top of the adjustments that came before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the background</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/background/</guid>
      <description>Processing high resolution images is a demanding task requiring a modern computer. In terms of both memory and CPU power, getting the best out of a typical 15, 20 or 25 megapixel image can quickly take your computer to its limits.&#xA;darktable&amp;rsquo;s requirements are no exception. All calculations are performed on 4 x 32bit floating point numbers. This is slower than “ordinary” 8 or 16 bit integer algebra, but eliminates all problems of tonal breaks or loss of information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tone curve</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-curve/</guid>
      <description>A classic digital photography tool to alter the tones of an image&amp;rsquo;s using curves.&#xA;This module is very similar to the rgb curve module but works in Lab color space.&#xA;Activate the color picker to show the picked values on the displayed histogram (Ctrl+click or right-click to use the picker in area mode). Numerical (Lab) values of the input and output (see below) at the selected spot or area are shown at the top left of the graph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tone equalizer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-equalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-equalizer/</guid>
      <description>Dodge and burn while preserving local contrast.&#xA;When used together with filmic rgb, this module replaces the need for other tone-mapping modules such as the base curve, shadows and highlights, tone curve and zone system (deprecated) modules. It works in linear RGB space and utilizes a user-defined mask to guide the dodging and burning adjustments, helping to preserve local contrast within the image.&#xA;The following diagram describes how the tone equalizer works:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>unbreak input profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/unbreak-input-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/unbreak-input-profile/</guid>
      <description>Add a correction curve to image data. This is required if you have selected certain input profiles in the input color profile module.&#xA;If you decide to use an ICC profile from the camera manufacturer in the input color profile module, a correction curve frequently needs to be pre-applied to image data to prevent the final output from looking too dark. This extra processing is not required if you use darktable&amp;rsquo;s standard or enhanced color matrices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velvia</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/velvia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/velvia/</guid>
      <description>Resaturate pixels in a weighted manner that gives more weight to blacks, whites and less saturated pixels.&#xA;Note: This module causes hue and brightness shifts that can be difficult to manage. Instead, use the color balance rgb module for color modifications.&#xA;🔗module controls strength The strength of the effect mid-tones bias Reduce the effect on mid-tones in order to avoid unnatural skin tones. Reducing the mid-tone bias decreases mid-tone protection and makes the overall velvia effect stronger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>views</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/views/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/views/</guid>
      <description>The functionality in darktable is separated into six different views:&#xA;lighttable Manage images and collections. darkroom Develop a single image. map Show geo-tagged images on a map and manually geo-tag new images. print Send images to a printer. slideshow Display images as a slideshow, processing them on-the-fly. tethering Remotely capture and save images taken with a connected camera. You can switch between views by clicking the view name at the top of the right-hand panel (the currently active view is highlighted) or by using one of the following keyboard shortcuts:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vignetting</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vignetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vignetting/</guid>
      <description>Apply a vignetting effect to the image.&#xA;Vignetting is a modification of the brightness and saturation at the borders of the image in a specified shape. Many of the parameters listed below can also be modified with a graphical control that overlays the image when the module has focus, showing the shape and extent of the effect.&#xA;Note: This module is known to provoke banding artifacts under certain conditions. You should consider activating the dither or posterize module to alleviate this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>watermark</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/watermark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/watermark/</guid>
      <description>Render a vector-based overlay onto your image. Watermarks are standard SVG documents and can be designed using Inkscape.&#xA;You can also use bitmap (PNG) images.&#xA;The SVG processor in darktable can also substitute strings within an SVG document, allowing image-dependent information to be included in the watermark.&#xA;User-designed watermarks should be placed into the directory $HOME/.config/darktable/watermarks. Once in place, use the reload button update the list of available watermarks.&#xA;The following is a list of variable strings that are supported for substitution within an SVG document.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>white balance</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/white-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/white-balance/</guid>
      <description>Adjust the white balance of the image by altering the temperature and tint, defining a coefficient for each RGB channel, or choosing from list of predefined white balance settings.&#xA;The default settings for this module are derived from the camera white balance stored in the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data.&#xA;White balance is not intended as a &amp;ldquo;creative&amp;rdquo; module &amp;ndash; its primary goal is to technically correct the white balance of the image ensuring that neutral colored objects in the scene are rendered with neutral colors in the image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) basic adjustments</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/basic-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/basic-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the quick access panel instead.&#xA;A convenience module that combines controls from exposure, highlight reconstruction, color balance and vibrance into a single module.&#xA;While this module can provide a quick and convenient way to make simple adjustments to an image, it must be used with care. Normally exposure adjustments should come before input color profile in the pixelpipe, and color adjustments should come after.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) channel mixer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/channel-mixer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/channel-mixer/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the color calibration module instead.&#xA;A simple yet powerful tool to manage color channels.&#xA;This module accepts red, green and blue channels as an input and provides red, green, blue, gray, hue, saturation and lightness channels as output. It allows you to independently control how much each input channel contributes to each output channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) contrast brightness saturation</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-brightness-saturation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-brightness-saturation/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 4.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the color balance rgb module instead.&#xA;A very basic tool for adjusting the contrast, brightness and saturation of an image. Please note that a number of other modules provide much more versatile methods of adjusting these parameters.&#xA;All module controls default to a neutral position (zero) and provide the ability to increase or decrease the relevant parameter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) crop and rotate</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop-rotate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop-rotate/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.8 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the crop module to crop the image, the rotate and perspective module to perform rotation and keystone correction, and the orientation module to flip the image on the horizontal/vertical axes.&#xA;Crop, rotate, and correct perspective distortions using on-screen guides.&#xA;Whenever the user interface of this module is in focus, the full uncropped image will be shown, overlaid with crop handles and optional guiding lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) defringe</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/defringe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/defringe/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the chromatic aberrations module instead.&#xA;Remove color fringing, which often results from Longitudinal Chromatic Aberrations (LCA), also known as Axial Chromatic Aberrations.&#xA;This module uses edge-detection. Where pixels are detected as a fringe, the color is rebuilt from less saturated neighboring pixels.&#xA;🔗module controls operation mode global average: This mode is usually the fastest but might show slightly incorrect previews at high magnification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) fill light</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/fill-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/fill-light/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the tone equalizer module or the exposure module with a drawn mask.&#xA;Locally modify exposure based on pixel lightness.&#xA;This module pushes exposure by increasing lightness with a Gaussian curve of a specified width, centered on a given lightness.&#xA;🔗module controls exposure The fill-light exposure (EV) center The median lightness impacted by the fill-light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) global tonemap</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/global-tonemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/global-tonemap/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the filmic rgb module instead.&#xA;Compress the tonal range of an HDR image into the limited tonal range of a typical LDR output file.&#xA;Global tonemap processes each pixel of an HDR image, without taking the local surrounding into account. This is generally faster than local tone mapping (deprecated), but might lead to less convincing results with very high-dynamic-range scenes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) invert</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/invert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/invert/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the negadoctor module instead.&#xA;Invert scanned negatives.&#xA;🔗module controls color of film material Clicking on the colored field will open a color selector dialog which offers you a choice of commonly used colors, or allows you to define an RGB color. You can also activate the color picker to take a color probe from your image – preferably from the unexposed border of your negative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) levels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/levels/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 4.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the rgb levels module instead.&#xA;Adjust black, white and mid-gray points.&#xA;The levels tool offers two modes of operation:&#xA;manual The levels tool shows a histogram of the image, and displays three bars with handles. Drag the handles to modify the black, middle-gray and white points in absolute values of image lightness (the L value from Lab).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) spot removal</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/spot-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/spot-removal/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the &amp;ldquo;cloning&amp;rdquo; tool in the retouch module instead.&#xA;Correct areas of an image (the target) using details from another area of the image (the source).&#xA;This module uses some of the shapes that are available for drawn masks (circles, ellipses and paths), and the user interface is similar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) tone mapping</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the tone equalizer module instead.&#xA;Compress the tonal range of HDR images so that they fit into the limits of an LDR image, using Durand&amp;rsquo;s 2002 algorithm.&#xA;The underlying algorithm uses a bilateral filter to decompose an image into a coarse base layer and a detail layer. The contrast of the base layer is compressed, while the detail layer is preserved, then both layers are re-combined.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) vibrance</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vibrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vibrance/</guid>
      <description> Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the vibrance control in the color balance rgb module instead.&#xA;Saturate and reduce the lightness of the most saturated pixels to make the colors more vivid.&#xA;🔗module controls vibrance The amount of vibrance to apply to the image. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) zone system</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/zone-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/zone-system/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the tone equalizer or multiple instances of the exposure module with parametric masks to narrow down on a zone.&#xA;Adjust the lightness of an image using Ansel Adams&amp;rsquo; zone system.&#xA;The lightness of the image (the L channel in Lab color space) is divided into a number of zones ranging from pure black to pure white.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>basic principles: luarc files</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/basic-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/basic-principles/</guid>
      <description>At startup, darktable will automatically run the Lua scripts $DARKTABLE/share/darktable/luarc and $HOME/.config/darktable/luarc (where $DARKTABLE represents the darktable installation directory and $HOME represents your home directory).&#xA;This is the only time darktable will run Lua scripts by itself. These scripts can register callbacks to perform actions on various darktable events. This callback mechanism is the primary method of triggering lua actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blend modes</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/blend-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/blend-modes/</guid>
      <description>Blend modes define how the input and output of a module are combined (blended) together before the module&amp;rsquo;s final output is passed to the next module in the pixelpipe.&#xA;Classic blending modes, designed for display-referred RGB (constrained to 0-100%), implicitly define a fulcrum at 50% (gray) or 100% (white) in their algorithms, depending on the blend mode. Because scene-referred is not subject to these restrictions, this fulcrum needs to be explicitly defined by the user when performing blending operations in the &amp;ldquo;RGB (scene)&amp;rdquo; color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>collections &amp; film rolls</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/collections/</guid>
      <description>A collection is a set of images matching a given selection criteria.&#xA;The most basic kind of collection is a film roll, which contains all of the images that have been imported from a specific folder on disk. Whenever you import images from the filesystem, those images are organized in a film roll whose name is derived from that of their parent folder.&#xA;You can easily construct other kinds of collection based on various image attributes (Exif data, filename, tags etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darkroom view layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/darkroom-view-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/darkroom-view-layout/</guid>
      <description>🔗left panel From top to bottom:&#xA;navigation Navigate and zoom the center view. snapshots Take and view snapshots for comparison with the current edit. duplicate manager View and manage duplicates. global color picker Select and display color information taken from parts of the image. tagging Manage tags. image information Display information about the current image. mask manager View and edit drawn shapes. export Export selected images to local files or external services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable-cli</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-cli/</guid>
      <description>The darktable-cli binary starts the command line interface variant of darktable which allows images to be exported.&#xA;This variant does not open any display &amp;ndash; it works in pure console mode without launching a GUI. This mode is particularly useful for servers running background jobs.&#xA;darktable-cli can be called with the following command line parameters:&#xA;darktable-cli [&amp;lt;input file or folder&amp;gt;] [&amp;lt;xmp file&amp;gt;] &amp;lt;output file or folder&amp;gt; [--width &amp;lt;max width&amp;gt;] [--height &amp;lt;max height&amp;gt;] [--hq &amp;lt;0|1|true|false&amp;gt;] [--upscale &amp;lt;0|1|true|false&amp;gt;] [--style &amp;lt;style name&amp;gt;] [--style-overwrite] [--apply-custom-presets &amp;lt;0|1|false|true&amp;gt;] [--out-ext &amp;lt;extension&amp;gt;] [--import &amp;lt;file or dir&amp;gt;] [--icc-type &amp;lt;type&amp;gt;] [--icc-file &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;] [--icc-intent &amp;lt;intent&amp;gt;] [--verbose] [--help [option]] [--core &amp;lt;darktable options&amp;gt;] The user must supply an input filename and an output filename.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>display profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/display-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/display-profile/</guid>
      <description>For darktable to faithfully render colors on screen it needs to find the correct display profile for your monitor. In general this requires your monitor to be properly calibrated and profiled, and it needs the profile to be correctly installed on your system. darktable queries your X display server&amp;rsquo;s xatom as well as the system service colord (if available) for the right profile. If required you can enforce a specific method in preferences &amp;gt; miscellaneous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>drawn masks</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/drawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/drawn/</guid>
      <description>With the drawn mask feature you can construct a mask by drawing shapes directly onto the image canvas. Shapes can be used alone or in combination. Once a shape has been drawn on an image it can be adjusted, removed, or reused in other modules.&#xA;Shapes are stored internally as vectors and are rendered with the required resolution during pixelpipe processing. Shapes are expressed in the coordinate system of the original image and are transformed along with the rest of the image by any active distorting modules in the pipe (lens correction, rotate and perspective for example).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>general</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/general/</guid>
      <description>Control the overall look and feel of darktable.&#xA;interface language Set the language of the user interface. The system default is marked with an * (needs a restart) theme Set the theme for the user interface. Aside from any aesthetic considerations, the recommended interface color for color evaluation is middle gray. Visual perception is affected by ambient brightness, and a low user interface brightness causes all kinds of illusions. Using a dark interface to retouch photos can therefore lead to excessive retouching (abuse of contrast and saturation) and to a photo that is too dark when printed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>how OpenCL works</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/how-opencl-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/how-opencl-works/</guid>
      <description>As you can imagine, the hardware architecture of GPUs can vary significantly. There are different manufacturers, and even different generations of GPUs from the same manufacturer may not be comparable. At the same time GPU manufacturers don&amp;rsquo;t normally disclose all the hardware details of their products to the public. One of the consequences of this is the need to use proprietary drivers under Linux, if you want to take full advantage of your graphics card.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import &amp; review</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/import-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/import-review/</guid>
      <description>Before you can do anything in darktable you must first add some images files to the library using the import module in the lighttable view. This will create entries for your images in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database so that it can keep track of the changes you make. There are three ways to import images, each accessible through buttons in the import module:&#xA;add to library This option adds images to the library without copying or moving &amp;ndash; your original files will stay in their current location and will not be altered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>importing sidecar files generated by other applications</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/sidecar-import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/sidecar-import/</guid>
      <description>When importing an image, darktable automatically checks if it is accompanied by a sidecar file. As well as looking for files named &amp;lt;basename&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;extension&amp;gt;.xmp and &amp;lt;basename&amp;gt;_&amp;lt;number&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;extension&amp;gt;.xmp (darktable&amp;rsquo;s XMP file naming formats) darktable also checks for the presence of a file in the form &amp;lt;basename&amp;gt;.xmp (the naming format for Lightroom&amp;rsquo;s XMP sidecar files). Files with the latter naming format will be read by darktable but will not be written to. Once the image has been imported, darktable will generate an additional XMP file using its own naming convention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lighttable view layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-view-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-view-layout/</guid>
      <description>🔗left panel From top to bottom:&#xA;import Import images from the filesystem or a connected camera. collections Filter the images displayed in the lighttable center panel &amp;ndash; also used to control the images displayed in the filmstrip and timeline modules. recently used collections View recently used collections of images. image information Display image information. lua scripts installer (optional) Install lua scripts. 🔗right panel From top to bottom:&#xA;selection Select images in the lighttable using simple criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>map view layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/map/map-view-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/map/map-view-layout/</guid>
      <description>🔗left panel These modules are identical to the lighttable view. From top to bottom:&#xA;collections Filter the list of images displayed in the map view. recently used collections View recently used collections of images. image information Display image information. 🔗right panel Here you can find the modules specific to the map view. From top to bottom:&#xA;find location Search for a place on map. locations Manage a hierarchical list of location tags and their corresponding regions on the map.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>module groups</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/module-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/module-groups/</guid>
      <description>A number of pre-defined module groups are shipped with darktable and are selectable as presets. These are summarized below.&#xA;All of these presets (with the exception of modules: deprecated and search only) also include the quick access panel. All except the modules: deprecated group include the search bar.&#xA;🔗modules: all This preset contains all modules, sorted according to the traditional module groupings used prior to darktable 3.4, as follows:&#xA;base modules The minimal set of modules normally required to render a presentable image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>multiple instances</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/multiple-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/multiple-instances/</guid>
      <description>Many of darktable&amp;rsquo;s modules can be applied more than once in the pixelpipe. Each instance of a module behaves independently, taking its input from the module below it in the pixelpipe and delivering its output to the next module.&#xA;As with the base instance of a module, all instances can be moved independently within the pixelpipe either by holding Ctrl+Shift while dragging &amp;amp; dropping or by choosing &amp;ldquo;move up&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;move down&amp;rdquo; in the multiple instances drop-down menu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>print view layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/print/print-view-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/print/print-view-layout/</guid>
      <description>The central area displays the image layout on the paper (the white area). Some gray borders may be displayed around the image to represent the printable area (the page minus the borders) not filled by the image.&#xA;The filmstrip below the image allows you to select more images.&#xA;🔗overlays When the mouse is over the bounding box of an image, its width and height are shown along its top and left, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>screen layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/screen-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/screen-layout/</guid>
      <description>The layout of all darktable views is similar and consists of a center area with panels at the edges:&#xA;center area : Contains information and functionality specific to the current view.&#xA;left panel : Contains modules primarily used to provide information.&#xA;right panel : Contains modules primarily used for image processing.&#xA;top banner : Contains information about the current darktable version and allows you to switch between views. Also used by some modules to show additional hints and messages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supported file formats</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/supported-file-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/supported-file-formats/</guid>
      <description>darktable supports a huge number of file formats from various camera manufacturers. In addition darktable can read a wide range of low- and high-dynamic-range images &amp;ndash; mainly for data exchange between darktable and other software.&#xA;In order for darktable to consider a file for import, it must have one of the following extensions (case independent): 3FR, ARI, ARW, BAY, BMQ, CAP, CINE, CR2, CR3, CRW, CS1, DC2, DCR, DNG, GPR, ERF, FFF, EXR, IA, IIQ, JPEG, JPG, JXL, K25, KC2, KDC, MDC, MEF, MOS, MRW, NEF, NRW, ORF, PEF, PFM, PNG, PXN, QTK, RAF, RAW, RDC, RW1, RW2, SR2, SRF, SRW, STI, TIF, TIFF, X3F</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tethering view layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/tethering-view-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/tethering-view-layout/</guid>
      <description>🔗left panel image information Display image information. 🔗right panel From top to bottom:&#xA;scopes A graphical depiction of the current image&amp;rsquo;s light levels and colors. This module can be moved to the left-hand panel if desired (see preferences &amp;gt; miscellaneous &amp;gt; position of the scopes module). session Session settings. live view Live view settings. camera settings Camera settings. metadata editor Edit metadata for selected images. tagging Tag selected images. 🔗bottom panel From left to right:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the pixelpipe &amp; module order</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/the-pixelpipe-and-module-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/the-pixelpipe-and-module-order/</guid>
      <description>The ordered sequence of processing modules operating on an input file to generate an output image is known as the &amp;ldquo;pixelpipe&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;The order of the pixelpipe is represented graphically by the order in which modules are presented in the user interface &amp;ndash; the pixelpipe starts with a RAW image at the bottom of the module list, and applies the processing modules one by one, piling up layer upon layer of processing from the bottom up, until it reaches the top of the list, where it outputs the fully processed image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>usage</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/slideshow/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/slideshow/usage/</guid>
      <description>The slideshow view is still in an early stage of development with only a basic set of features.&#xA;If you don&amp;rsquo;t need the auto-advance mode, you could even use the sticky preview feature instead.&#xA;spacebar start and stop auto-advance mode which automatically switches to the next images every five seconds by default. ESC leave slideshow mode and return to lighttable view. + or increase delay between each image. up arrow - or decrease delay between each image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>usage</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/usage/</guid>
      <description>The tool is organized into three tabs in the upper part and a text output frame in the lower part.&#xA;The first tab is used to define the source image, the second tab defines the reference (target) and the third tab contains the controls to generate the resulting darktable style.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>zoomable lighttable</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/zoomable-lighttable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/zoomable-lighttable/</guid>
      <description>The zoomable lighttable mode provides an alternative way to navigate large collections of images, but with some similarities to the filemanager mode (described below).&#xA;🔗controls zoom Scroll with the mouse wheel to zoom in and out of the lighttable (compared to Ctrl+scroll in filemanager mode). Zooming the thumbnails does not change the number of thumbnails per row, so the lighttable can exceed the visible area on all sides. navigate Hold down the left mouse button and drag to move the lighttable around and navigate through your collection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a simple lua example</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/a-simple-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/a-simple-example/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple example that will print some code on the console. Create a file called luarc in darktable&amp;rsquo;s configuration directory (usually $HOME/.config/darktable/) and add the following line to it:&#xA;print(&amp;#34;Hello World !&amp;#34;) Start darktable and you will see the sentence &amp;ldquo;Hello World !&amp;rdquo; printed on the console. Nothing fancy but it&amp;rsquo;s a start.&#xA;At this point, there is nothing darktable-specific in the script. We simply use Lua&amp;rsquo;s standard print function to print a string.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>activating OpenCL in darktable</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/activate-opencl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/activate-opencl/</guid>
      <description>Using OpenCL in darktable requires that your PC is equipped with a suitable graphics card and that it has the required libraries in place. Most modern graphics cards from NVIDIA, Intel or AMD come with full OpenCL support. The OpenCL compiler is normally shipped as part of the proprietary graphics driver and is used as a dynamic library called libOpenCL.so. This library must be in a folder where it can be found by your system&amp;rsquo;s dynamic linker.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>culling</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/culling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/culling/</guid>
      <description>Culling mode allows you to display images side by side for easy comparison.&#xA;🔗controls zoom In culling mode, you can zoom into images (up to 100%) by holding Ctrl while scrolling with the mouse wheel. Pan within zoomed images with click+drag. By default, zooming and panning are synchronized between all visible images. If you want to zoom or pan only a specific image, add the Shift modifier to the above actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable-generate-cache</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-generate-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-generate-cache/</guid>
      <description>The darktable-generate-cache binary updates darktable&amp;rsquo;s thumbnail cache. Invoke this program to generate all missing thumbnails in the background when your computer is idle.&#xA;darktable-generate-cache can be called with the following command line parameters:&#xA;darktable-generate-cache [-h, --help] [--version] [--min-mip &amp;lt;0-8&amp;gt;] [-m, --max-mip &amp;lt;0-8&amp;gt;] [--min-imgid &amp;lt;N&amp;gt;] [--max-imgid &amp;lt;N&amp;gt;] [--core &amp;lt;darktable options&amp;gt;] All parameters are optional. If started without parameters darktable-generate-cache uses reasonable defaults.&#xA;-h, --help Display usage information and terminate. --version Display copyright and version information and terminate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>examples</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/examples/</guid>
      <description>The following sections show two typical use cases for the tethering view.&#xA;🔗studio setup with screening This is a pretty common use case. You have your studio and subject set up, the camera is connected to your computer and tethering view is active in darktable. You work at the camera and take images. Whenever you like, you can review the images directly on your computer monitor instead of using the camera LCD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filmstrip</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/filmstrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/filmstrip/</guid>
      <description>The filmstrip, when enabled, is shown at the bottom of the screen (except in the lighttable view, where it is replaced with the timeline module) and displays the images from the current collection (set in the lighttable view). You can navigate the filmstrip by scrolling with the mouse wheel.&#xA;The filmstrip allows you to interact with images while you are not in the lighttable view. For example, while developing an image in darkroom mode, you can switch to another image by clicking its thumbnail in the filmstrip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/import/</guid>
      <description>Control default file naming conventions used when importing images.&#xA;🔗session options The following options define the default naming pattern for use in the &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; import&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; import from camera&amp;rdquo; options in the import module, or when taking photos in the tethering view.&#xA;The naming pattern consists of three parts: a base part defining the parent folder, a session part defining a sub directory (which is specific to the individual import session), and a file name part defining the filename structure for each imported image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>local copies</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/local-copies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/local-copies/</guid>
      <description>Many users have huge image collections stored on extra hard drives in their desktop computer, or on an external storage medium (RAID NAS, external hard drives etc.).&#xA;It is a common requirement to develop a number of images while travelling using a laptop and then later synchronize them back to the original storage medium. However, copying images manually from the main storage to the laptop and back is cumbersome and prone to errors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>parametric masks</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/parametric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/parametric/</guid>
      <description>The parametric mask feature offers fine-grained selective control over how individual pixels are masked. It does this by automatically generating an intermediate blend mask from user-defined parameters. These parameters are color coordinates rather than the geometrical coordinates used in drawn masks.&#xA;For each data channel of a module (e.g. Lab, RGB) and several virtual data channels (e.g. hue, saturation) you can construct a per-channel opacity function. Depending on each pixel&amp;rsquo;s value for a given data channel this function calculates a blending factor between 0 and 1 (100%) for that pixel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>presets</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/presets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/presets/</guid>
      <description>Presets allow you to store commonly-used module settings for future use. Some modules already come with pre-defined (internal) presets and you may also define your own (user-defined). Both internal and user-defined presets can be shown by clicking the presets menu in the module header.&#xA;Most of the functionality described here applies to processing modules only. However, presets can also be used with some utility modules. When used with utility modules, the functionality to auto-apply or auto-show presets based on image Exif data is not available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>process</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/process/</guid>
      <description>This section is intended to get you comfortable processing images in the darkroom view using a scene-referred workflow. You are advised to follow the guidelines provided below, up to the end of the image processing in 3 modules section and then choose other areas to learn as-and-when you need to use those techniques in your images.&#xA;🔗getting started 🔗take a well-exposed photograph Good image processing techniques start in the camera &amp;ndash; a well-exposed image (without blown highlights or heavily crushed blacks) will always make post-processing much more straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>quick access panel</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/quick-access-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/quick-access-panel/</guid>
      <description>The quick access panel allows you to access widgets from a number of processing modules all in one place.&#xA;You can add new widgets to the panel by&#xA;right-clicking on the &amp;ldquo;hamburger&amp;rdquo; icon at the top-left of the panel using the manage module layouts screen Ctrl+clicking on a widget in a processing module while in visual shortcut mapping mode Click on the icon to the right of the module name to open the full version of that module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rendering method</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/rendering-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/rendering-method/</guid>
      <description>darktable can render colors either with its own internal algorithms or by using the external library LittleCMS2. darktable&amp;rsquo;s internal method is, by an order of magnitude, faster than the external one. The external option gives you a choice of the rendering intent and might offer a slightly higher accuracy in some cases.&#xA;You can change the default method in preferences &amp;gt; processing &amp;gt; always use LittleCMS 2 to apply output color profile</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>source image</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/source-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/source-image/</guid>
      <description>In the “source image” tab you set your source image, which requires two elements. The first element is an input file in Lab Portable Float Map format (extension .pfm). The source file represents the largely unmodified data as the camera sees it. Information about how to take photos of a color reference card and produce a .pfm output file are described below. The second element is a chart file that contains a formal description of the underlying color reference card&amp;rsquo;s layout (extension .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the history stack</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/history-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/history-stack/</guid>
      <description>The history stack stores the entire editing history for a given image, in the order in which those edits were applied. It is saved to darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database and the image&amp;rsquo;s XMP sidecar file and persists between editing sessions.&#xA;Each time a processing module is enabled, disabled, moved or amended a new entry is added to the top of the history stack.&#xA;The history stack can be queried and modified within the history stack module in the darkroom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>thumbnails</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/thumbnails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/thumbnails/</guid>
      <description>Each image in the current collection is represented by a thumbnail in the lighttable view and filmstrip module. A cache of the most recently used thumbnails is stored in a file on disk and loaded into memory at startup.&#xA;🔗thumbnail creation A thumbnail is created when an image is imported into darktable for the first time, after an image has been modified in the darkroom, or when revisiting an image whose thumbnail is no longer available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>undo/redo</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/undo-redo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/undo-redo/</guid>
      <description>Most changes made within the lighttable are recorded and can be reverted to a previous state. This includes modifications to color labels, ratings, geo-localization, tags, metadata, orientation, copy/paste of history, image duplication, or application of a style. Note that the facility to undo/redo actions is unlimited in the number of steps while in the lighttable view, but it is reset each time you switch to a different view.&#xA;Press Ctrl+Z to undo the last modification and Ctrl+Y to redo the last undone modification (if any).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>memory &amp; performance tuning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/mem-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/mem-performance/</guid>
      <description>🔗memory requirements Processing a Raw image in darktable requires a great deal of system memory. A simple calculation makes this clear: For a 20 megapixel image, darktable requires a 4x32-bit floating point cell to store each pixel, meaning that each full image of this size will require approximately 300MB of memory just to store the image data. In order to actually process this image through a given module, darktable needs at least two buffers (input and output) of this size, with more complex modules potentially requiring several additional buffers for intermediate data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>combining drawn &amp; parametric masks</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/drawn-and-parametric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/drawn-and-parametric/</guid>
      <description>Drawn and parametric masks can be used in combination to form a single mask that can be applied to a module.&#xA;There are two main elements which control how individual masks are combined: the polarity setting of each individual mask (defined by the plus or minus buttons) and the setting in the “combine masks” combobox.&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;combine masks&amp;rdquo; combobox contains the following options, defining how the drawn and parametric masks will be combined:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable-chart</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-chart/</guid>
      <description>The darktable-chart binary is a dedicated utility to create styles out of pairs of images such as RAW+JPEG with in-camera processing. Details about its usage can be found in the using darktable-chart section.&#xA;darktable-chart can either start a GUI or be used as a command-line program.&#xA;darktable-chart [--help] [&amp;lt;input Lab pfm file&amp;gt;] [&amp;lt;cht file&amp;gt;] [&amp;lt;reference cgats/it8 or Lab pfm file&amp;gt;] All parameters are optional, however, if you want to supply the second file name you also need to supply the first one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/export/</guid>
      <description>darktable is a non-destructive editor, which means that all changes are recorded in the library database (with a backup stored in an XMP sidecar file), and the original Raw file is left untouched. You therefore need to export images in order to bake your edits into an output file that can be distributed outside of darktable.&#xA;Choose an export scenario.&#xA;The export module offers many options, but by far the most common use is to “save a developed raw image as a JPEG”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>full preview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/full-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-modes/full-preview/</guid>
      <description>From any of the lighttable modes, you can display a fully-zoomed preview of the image that is currently under the mouse pointer by pressing and holding down W. This is useful to more closely inspect an image while rating and selecting images.&#xA;Pressing and holding Ctrl+W fully zooms into the image and also identifies any regions of sharpness in the image that may indicate image focus. For this tool to work the input image needs to hold an embedded JPEG thumbnail, which is the case for most raw files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lighttable</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lighttable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lighttable/</guid>
      <description>Control functionality in the lighttable view and modules.&#xA;🔗general hide built-in presets for utility modules If enabled, only user-defined presets will be shown in presets menu for utility modules &amp;ndash; built-in presets will be hidden (default off). use single-click in the collections module Enable &amp;ldquo;single click&amp;rdquo; mode in the collections module, which allows ranges to be selected (default off). expand a single utility module at a time Controls how utility modules are expanded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>manage module layouts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/manage-module-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/manage-module-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Manage the layout and grouping of processing modules and the quick access panel.&#xA;This maintenance screen can be accessed from the presets menu beside the module search box or module group icons (below the scopes module in the darkroom view). Ctrl+click on the preset menu to open this screen directly.&#xA;Settings are automatically saved when you exit the screen. Click reset to abandon any changes made in the current editing session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>module controls</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/module-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/module-controls/</guid>
      <description>This section describes how to interact with processing module controls.&#xA;🔗sliders Sliders offer five different methods of interaction, depending on the level of control you require.&#xA;left-click (set) Click anywhere in the slider area to set the value. You can also click and drag to change it. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to aim for the triangle or even the line &amp;ndash; you can click anywhere in the entire height of the slider, including the label.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>printing labeled images</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/printing-labeled-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/printing-labeled-images/</guid>
      <description>The first example showed us the very basics of lua and allowed us to check that everything was working properly. Now let&amp;rsquo;s do something a little bit more complex. Let&amp;rsquo;s try to print a list of images that have a &amp;ldquo;red&amp;rdquo; label attached to them. But first of all, what is an image?&#xA;local darktable = require &amp;#34;darktable&amp;#34; local debug = require &amp;#34;darktable.debug&amp;#34; print(darktable.debug.dump(darktable.database[1])) Running the code above will produce a lot of output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reference values</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/reference-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/reference-values/</guid>
      <description>The “reference values” tab determines the target values to which the source image must to be modified by the resulting style. You can either supply reference values in the form of measured data of your color reference card (mode “cie/it8 file”), or you can supply a photographic image (mode “color chart image”) much in the same way as described above. This second image must also be supplied in Lab Portable Float Map format.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rendering intent</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/rendering-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/rendering-intent/</guid>
      <description>If rendering with LittleCMS2 is activated (see rendering method) you can define how to handle out-of-gamut colors when converting between color spaces. A selection box in the export, output color profile, and soft proof modules gives you a choice of the following rendering intents:&#xA;perceptual Best suited to photographs as it maintains the relative position of colors. This is usually the best choice. relative colorimetric Out-of-gamut colors are converted to colors having the same lightness, but different saturation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>setting up OpenCL</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/setting-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/setting-up/</guid>
      <description>The huge diversity of systems and the marked differences between OpenCL vendors and driver versions makes it impossible to give an comprehensive overview of how to setup OpenCL. We only can give you an example, in this case for NVIDIA driver version 542.29.06 on Fedora 39. We hope that this will serve as a basic introduction and will help you to solve any problems specific to your setup.&#xA;The principle OpenCL function flow is like this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>star ratings &amp; color labels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/star-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/star-color/</guid>
      <description>Star ratings and color labels help you to sort and rank images according to your own criteria. An image&amp;rsquo;s star rating and color labels can be displayed over thumbnails in the lighttable view and filmstrip module.&#xA;🔗star ratings You can give an image a rating from zero to five stars. Whenever you import images, each image receives a default rating which you can define in the import module. You can also mark an image as “rejected”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>top panel</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/top-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/top-panel/</guid>
      <description>The top panel appears in all darktable views and provides access to common functions.&#xA;🔗On the left-hand-side filter / sort Choose how to filter and sort the images. Criteria can be altered in the collection filters module or by clicking on the icon. sort order Switch the sort order (ascending / descending). 🔗On the right-hand-side grouping Expand or collapse grouped images. thumbnail overlays Define what information is overlaid on to thumbnails in the lighttable/filmstrip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/tethering/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>This troubleshooting guide can be used to verify whether or not your camera can be used with tethering. This is done using the same (gphoto2) tool that darktable uses to interface with your camera.&#xA;Before you start, you first need to find your camera port name. Usually the port &amp;ldquo;usb:&amp;rdquo; is sufficient and is therefore used in the following guide.&#xA;🔗is your camera detected? The following command will verify that your camera is connected to the computer and detected by gphoto2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>undo and redo</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/undo-redo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/undo-redo/</guid>
      <description>While you are editing your image, darktable records all of the modifications you make to that image. This means that it is possible to undo and redo changes to recover a previous editing state. Note that the undo/redo facility is unlimited in the number of steps while editing an image, but is reset each time the darkroom is switched to a new image.&#xA;Press Ctrl+Z to undo the last modification and Ctrl+Y to redo the last undone modification (if any).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>adding a simple shortcut</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/simple-shortcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/simple-shortcut/</guid>
      <description>So far, all our scripts have done things during startup. This is of limited use and doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow us to react to real user actions. To do more advanced things we need to register a function that will be called on a given event. The most common event to react to is a keyboard shortcut.&#xA;darktable = require &amp;#34;darktable&amp;#34; local function hello_shortcut(event, shortcut) darktable.print(&amp;#34;Hello, I just received &amp;#39;&amp;#34;..event.. &amp;#34;&amp;#39; with parameter &amp;#39;&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>curves</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/curves/</guid>
      <description>The base curve, tone curve and rgb curve modules use curves to control the tones in the image. These modules have some common features that warrant separate discussion.&#xA;🔗nodes In their default state, curves are straight lines, defined by two anchor nodes at the top-right and bottom-left of the graph. You can move the nodes to modify the curve or generate new nodes by clicking on the curve. Ctrl+click to generate a new node at the x-location of the mouse pointer and the corresponding y-location of the current curve &amp;ndash; this adds a node without the risk of accidentally modifying the curve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darkroom</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/darkroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/darkroom/</guid>
      <description>Control functionality in the darkroom view and associated modules.&#xA;🔗general scroll down to increase mask parameters By default, scrolling your mouse up increases the value of the relevant shape parameters in drawn masks. Set this preference to reverse the behavior (default off). middle mouse button zooms to 200% When enabled, clicking the middle mouse button on the image canvas causes the zoom level to toggle between fit, 100% and 200%. When disabled, the middle mouse button toggles between fit and 100%.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable-cltest</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-cltest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-cltest/</guid>
      <description>The darktable-cltest binary checks if there is a usable OpenCL environment on your system that darktable can use. It emits some debug output that is equivalent to calling darktable -d opencl and then terminates.&#xA;darktable-cltest is called without command line parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable&#39;s color spaces</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Input images are either RGB files (like JPEGs or TIFFs) or camera RAWs. Both store visual information as a combination of primary colors (e.g. red, green and blue) which together describe a light emission to be recreated by a display.&#xA;The following image illustrates this concept.&#xA;The left-hand-side of the image depicts a colored light that we need to represent digitally. We can use three ideal color filters to decompose this light into three colored primary lights at different intensities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>image grouping</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/grouping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/grouping/</guid>
      <description>Grouping images helps to improve the structure and clarity of your image collection when displayed in the lighttable view.&#xA;You can combine images into a group by selecting them and clicking the “group” button in the actions on selection module, or by pressing Ctrl+G. Likewise, you can remove selected images from a group by clicking the “ungroup” button, or pressing Ctrl+Shift+G.&#xA;Duplicated images are automatically grouped together. Similarly, if you import multiple images from the same directory, having the same base name, but different extensions (eg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>keyboard shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/keyboard-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/keyboard-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Much of the functionality in darktable can be controlled via keyboard shortcuts, which can be customised in preferences &amp;gt; shortcuts.&#xA;Press the H key (for help) in any darktable view to show a list of all shortcuts that are applicable to the current view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mask refinement &amp; additional controls</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/refinement-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/refinement-controls/</guid>
      <description>When a parametric or drawn mask is active, several additional sliders are shown which allow the mask to be further refined.&#xA;details threshold This control allows you to alter the opacity of the mask based on the amount of detail in the image. Use this slider to select either areas with lots of detail (positive values) or areas that are flat and lacking in detail (negative values). The default (zero) effectively bypasses details refinement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>possible problems &amp; solutions</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/problems-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/problems-solutions/</guid>
      <description>darktable will detect OpenCL run-time errors automatically. On detecting an error, it will then reprocess everything on the CPU. While this will slow down processing it should not affect the end result.&#xA;There can be various reasons why OpenCL might fail during the initialization phase. OpenCL depends on hardware requirements and on the presence of certain drivers and libraries. In addition all these have to fit in terms of maker, model and revision number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>process</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/process/</guid>
      <description>If all of the required settings in the &amp;ldquo;source image&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;reference values&amp;rdquo; tabs are ready you can move on to the “process” tab.&#xA;First, you need to tell darktable-chart which of the patches represents the gray ramp. In the screenshot displayed above, the gray ramp is positioned in the lower part of the color reference chart, denoted as &amp;ldquo;GS00&amp;hellip;GS23&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;number of final patches&amp;rdquo; input defines how many editable color patches the resulting style will use within the color look up table module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wavelets</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/wavelets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/wavelets/</guid>
      <description>Wavelets are used to separate (or decompose) an image into a number of distinct layers, each containing a different level of detail. After decomposing an image in this way, a module can limit its processing to one or more of these detail layers, and then piece the layers back together again at the end to form its output. This allows us to be surgical about which features in the image we wish to impact when working with a module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>deprecated modules</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/deprecated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/deprecated/</guid>
      <description>The darktable team regularly reviews old modules and updates their implementation where issues are found or updated science means that they can be improved. Most of the time we try to update existing modules with new functionality but occasionally that becomes problematic, often due to the overhead of having to maintain multiple versions of the module. In such circumstances a new replacement module is created and the old module becomes deprecated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable-cmstest</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-cmstest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/darktable-cmstest/</guid>
      <description>The darktable-cmstest binary (Linux only) investigates whether the color management subsystem of your computer is correctly configured and displays some useful information about the installed monitor profile(s).&#xA;darktable-cmstest is called without command line parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>exporting images with lua</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/exporting-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/exporting-images/</guid>
      <description>So far we have learned to use lua to adapt darktable to our particular workflow. Let&amp;rsquo;s look now at how to use lua to easily export images to an online service. If you are able to upload an image to a service via the command line then you can use lua to integrate this into darktable&amp;rsquo;s user interface.&#xA;In this next example we will use lua to export via scp. A new storage type will appear in darktable&amp;rsquo;s UI that will export images to a remote target via the copy mechanism in ssh.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>making input images for darktable-chart</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/making-input-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/darktable-chart/making-input-images/</guid>
      <description>To start with, you need a suitable photo of your color reference card in RAW+JPEG format. It goes beyond the scope of this manual to explain the details of how to take this photo, but in a nutshell you need to make the shot on a sunny day around midday with the light source (the sun) shining at an angle onto the card. You need to avoid any glare in the image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>metadata and tagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/metadata-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/metadata-tagging/</guid>
      <description>darktable allows you to store additional information about your images to allow them to be more easily searched and grouped. This information is stored in darktable&amp;rsquo;s database and XMP sidecar files and can also be included within exported images.&#xA;🔗metadata Metadata (e.g. title, description) is free-format text that usually differs for each image. You can add metadata to images in the metadata editor module.&#xA;🔗tagging Tags are usually shared between multiple images and are used to categorise and group them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raster masks</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/raster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/masks/raster/</guid>
      <description>As described in the previous sections, the final output of a module&amp;rsquo;s mask (the combined effect of any drawn and parameteric masks) is a grayscale raster image representing the extent to which the module&amp;rsquo;s effect should be applied to each pixel. This raster image is stored internally for active modules and can be subsequently reused by other modules in the pixelpipe.&#xA;As with any mask, if the opacity value for a pixel in a raster mask is zero the module&amp;rsquo;s input passed through the module unchanged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>unbounded colors</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/unbounded-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/unbounded-colors/</guid>
      <description>Screens and most image file formats can only encode RGB intensities confined within a certain range. For example, images encoded on 8 bits can only contain values from 0 to 255, images on 10 bits from 0 to 1023, and so on… Graphic standards postulate that the maximum of that range, no matter its actual value, will always represent the maximum brightness that the display medium is able to render, usually between 100 and 160 Cd/m² (or nits) depending on the actual standard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>variables</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/variables/</guid>
      <description>darktable supports variable substitution in a number of modules and preference settings. For example:&#xA;Defining file names in the export module Displaying image information in the darkroom&amp;rsquo;s image information line Displaying image information in the lighttable&amp;rsquo;s overlays and tooltips (see preferences &amp;gt; lighttable) Placing text on an image in the watermark processing module 🔗available variables The following variables are available, though they may not all be applicable in every context:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>building user interface elements</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/building-ui-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/building-ui-elements/</guid>
      <description>Our previous example was a bit limited. In particular the use of a preference for the export path wasn&amp;rsquo;t very nice. We can do better than that by adding elements to the user interface in the export dialog.&#xA;UI elements are created via the darktable.new_widget function. This function takes a type of widget as a parameter and returns a new object corresponding to that widget. You can then set various fields in that widget to set its parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>possible color artifacts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-artifacts/</guid>
      <description>There are some infrequent situations that still can lead to problematic results unless the user takes some action. Some modules in Lab color space, like levels and monochrome, rely on the fact that the L channels carries all lightness information, with the a and b channels purely representing chroma and hue. Unbounded colors with negative L values are especially problematic to these modules and can lead to black pixel artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>processing</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/processing/</guid>
      <description>Control how images are processed.&#xA;🔗image processing always use LittleCMS 2 to apply output color profile If this option is activated, darktable will use the LittleCMS 2 system library to apply the output color profile instead of its own internal routines. This is significantly slower than the default but might give more accurate results in some cases. If the given ICC is LUT-based or contains both a LUT and a matrix, darktable will use LittleCMS 2 to render the colors regardless of this parameter&amp;rsquo;s value (default off).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>purge_non_existing_images.sh</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/purge_non_existing_images_sh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/program-invocation/purge_non_existing_images_sh/</guid>
      <description>Find and remove entries from the library database referencing images that no longer exist in the filesystem. You must close darktable before running this script.&#xA;The script can be called with the following command line parameters:&#xA;purge_non_existing_images.sh [-c|--configdir &amp;lt;path&amp;gt;] [-l|--library &amp;lt;path&amp;gt;] [-p|--purge] Run the script with no options to perform a &amp;ldquo;dry run&amp;rdquo;, which generates a report of the missing files without committing any changes to the database.&#xA;The available options are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable&#39;s color dimensions</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-dimensions/</guid>
      <description>This section defines the perceptual properties of color, both conceptually and quantitatively, in order to characterize and quantify the creative and corrective adjustments made to color in darktable.&#xA;🔗definitions Color properties like &amp;ldquo;saturation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;brightness&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;lightness&amp;rdquo; have passed into common usage but are largely misused and often used to mean different things. In color science, each of these terms has a precise meaning.&#xA;There are two frameworks within which color properties may be analyzed and described:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable&#39;s color pipeline</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Most image processing applications come from the 1990s and/or inherit a 1990s workflow. These applications processed images encoded with 8 bit unsigned integers because it was more memory- and computationally-efficient. However, due to the use of an integer format (which implies rounding errors) they had to apply a &amp;ldquo;gamma&amp;rdquo; (essentially a transfer function applying a power 1/2.2 or 1/2.4 to encode the RGB values) and increase the bit-depth in the low-lights in order to reduce rounding errors there (humans are very sensitive to low-light details).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scheduling profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/scheduling-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/scheduling-profile/</guid>
      <description>darktable can use the CPU and one or several OpenCL capable GPUs. Depending on the relative performance of these devices, users can choose among certain scheduling profiles to optimize performance. This is achieved by setting the configuration parameter preferences &amp;gt; processing &amp;gt; OpenCL &amp;gt; OpenCL scheduling profile, which offers the following choices:&#xA;default If an OpenCL-capable GPU is found darktable uses it for processing the center image view while the navigation preview window is processed on the CPU in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>security</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/security/</guid>
      <description>Control whether warning messages are shown before undertaking certain activities.&#xA;🔗general ask before removing images from the library Always ask before removing image information from darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database, where the xmp file is retained (default on). ask before deleting images from disk Always ask before deleting an image file (default on). ask before discarding history stack Always ask before discarding the history stack of an image (default on). try to use trash when deleting images Instead of physically deleting images from disk, attempt to put them into the system&amp;rsquo;s trash bin (default on).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sharing scripts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/sharing-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/sharing-scripts/</guid>
      <description>So far, all of our lua code has been in luarc. That&amp;rsquo;s a good way to develop your script but not very practical for distribution. We need to make this into a proper lua module. To do that, we save the code in a separate file (scp-storage.lua in this case):&#xA;--[[ SCP STORAGE a simple storage to export images via scp AUTHOR Jérémy Rosen (jeremy.rosen@enst-bretagne.fr) INSTALLATION * copy this file in $CONFIGDIR/lua/ where CONFIGDIR is your darktable configuration directory * add the following line in the file $CONFIGDIR/luarc require &amp;#34;scp-storage&amp;#34; USAGE * select &amp;#34;Export via SCP&amp;#34; in the storage selection menu * set the target directory * export your images LICENSE GPLv2 ]] darktable = require &amp;#34;darktable&amp;#34; dtutils = require &amp;#34;lib/dtutils&amp;#34; dtutils.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>midi device support</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/midi-device-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/midi-device-support/</guid>
      <description>🔗introduction MIDI is a communication protocol used by many electronic musical instruments (&amp;ldquo;pianos&amp;rdquo;), digital audio studio equipment (&amp;ldquo;control surfaces&amp;rdquo;) and even dedicated &amp;ldquo;photo editing keyboards&amp;rdquo; like the Loupedeck/Loupedeck+ (but not their later products). Such devices commonly feature sets of keys/buttons and sometimes encoders (knobs/rotors) and faders (sliders). Buttons sometimes feature lights, which makes them ideal for toggling features in darktable, because the lights can reflect the current (on/off) status. Encoders and faders are ideal for use with on-screen sliders in processing modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>calling lua from dbus</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/calling-from-dbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/calling-from-dbus/</guid>
      <description>It is possible to send a lua command to darktable via its DBus interface. The method org.darktable.service.Remote.Lua takes a single string parameter which is interpreted as a lua command. The command will be executed in the current lua context and should return either nil or a string. The result will be passed back as the result of the DBus method.&#xA;If the Lua call results in an error, the DBus method call will return an error org.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contributing to dtdocs</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/contributing/</guid>
      <description>This page defines the style guide for dtdocs and information about how to contribute to the project.&#xA;It is included in the user manual so that you can see how the page is rendered as well as how it is written. Please go to GitHub to see the source for this page.&#xA;The manual structure and content have been carefully considered based on the following criteria:&#xA;The manual should be comprehensive &amp;ndash; it should describe all of the functionality available in darktable It should have a consistent and logical structure and every piece of functionality should have its own logical place within that structure It should be as long as necessary but as short as possible &amp;ndash; brevity is a must It should be objective Functionality should be explained once and only once (with the exception of the basic workflow guidelines in the overview section) Images should be included only where necessary to improve understanding of key principles and should not contain text unless it is unavoidable We are generally not interested in:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>multiple devices</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/multiple-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/multiple-devices/</guid>
      <description>The scheduling of OpenCL devices can be optimized on most systems using the “OpenCL scheduling profile” settings. However, if your system is equipped with more than one GPU, you might want to set the relative device priority manually. To do this you need to select the “default” scheduling profile and change the settings in the “opencl_device_priority” configuration parameter.&#xA;It is important to understand how darktable uses OpenCL devices. Each processing sequence of an image &amp;ndash; to convert an input to the final output using a history stack &amp;ndash; is run in a pixelpipe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCL still does not run for me</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/still-doesnt-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/opencl/still-doesnt-work/</guid>
      <description>As has been mentioned, OpenCL systems come with a huge variety of setups: different GPU manufacturers and models, varying amounts of GPU memory, different drivers, different distributions etc..&#xA;Many of the potential problems will only appear with very specific combinations of these factors. As the darktable developers only have access to a small fraction of these variations, please understand that we might not be able to fix your specific problem. There is not much we can do if we are unable to reproduce your issue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>storage</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/storage/</guid>
      <description>The following options are related to darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database and XMP sidecar files.&#xA;🔗database create database snapshot Specifies how often darktable should create database snapshots. Options are &amp;ldquo;never&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;once a month&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;once a week&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;once a day&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;on close&amp;rdquo; (default &amp;ldquo;once a week&amp;rdquo;) how many snapshots to keep Number of snapshots to keep after creating a new snapshot, not counting database backups taken when moving between darktable versions. Enter &amp;ldquo;-1&amp;rdquo; to store an unlimited number of snapshots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>translating dtdocs</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/translating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/translating/</guid>
      <description>Translation of the darktable documentation is done via our Weblate instance.&#xA;You can either use Weblate&amp;rsquo;s web UI to translate the documentation or download the translation from Weblate to your computer, edit it, and then upload the changes.&#xA;Please do all translation work through Weblate. We will not accept pull requests directly on github to update PO files.&#xA;🔗Making a new branch in git Make a new branch to work on it in git.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>using darktable from a lua script</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/darktable-from-lua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/darktable-from-lua/</guid>
      <description>Warning: This feature is very experimental. It is known that several elements don&amp;rsquo;t yet work in library mode. Careful testing is highly recommended.&#xA;The lua interface allows you to use darktable from any lua script. This will load darktable as a library and provide you with most of the lua API (darktable is configured headless, so the functions relating to the user interface are not available).&#xA;As an example, the following program will print the list of all images in your library:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>batch-editing images</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/batch-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/batch-editing/</guid>
      <description>Batch-editing is the process of developing images in a semantically-related series that are expected to have a consistent final look, often with the intent of publishing the images in catalogues, magazines or books. It can be a tedious, frustrating and unexciting task, so darktable includes functionality to help make it faster and more reliable.&#xA;🔗preparation 🔗shooting color checkers Shooting a color checker on-location can save a tremendous amount of time during batch post-processing of a series of images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lua API</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/api/</guid>
      <description>darktable&amp;rsquo;s Lua API is documented in its own manual with a detailed description of all data structures and functions. You can download the API manual from here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>miscellaneous</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description>🔗interface load default shortcuts at startup When launching the application, darktable loads default shortcuts first, and then loads user-defined shortcuts on top. This allows default shortcuts to be overridden with a new action but prevents them from being deleted (since the deleted shortcut will be automatically reloaded on the next restart). Deactivate this preference to stop loading default shortcuts on startup &amp;ndash; only load the user-defined ones (including any defaults that you have not subsequently deleted or overridden).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>other resources</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/other-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/other-resources/</guid>
      <description>For help and support with using darktable you are encouraged to ask questions on the main discussion forums at discuss.pixls.us.&#xA;The official places to obtain information concerning darktable are the following:&#xA;darktable.org GitHub wiki The following articles provide some useful background information about darktable&amp;rsquo;s scene-referred workflow:&#xA;darktable 3.0 for dummies in 3 modules darktable 3.0 for dummies &amp;ndash; hardcore edition darktable 3.0: RGB or Lab? Which modules? Help! darktable&amp;rsquo;s filmic FAQ Introducing color calibration module The following resources can provide a deeper understanding of the functionality of some specific processing modules:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>You can perform almost any action in darktable with a keyboard/mouse shortcut. You can also use various other input devices, including MIDI devices and game controllers &amp;ndash; see the midi device support section for details. These are referred to as external devices or just devices in this guide.&#xA;🔗defining shortcuts A shortcut is a combination of key or button presses and/or mouse or device movements that performs an action in darktable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>presets</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/presets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/presets/</guid>
      <description>This menu provides an overview of the presets that are defined for darktable&amp;rsquo;s modules, and allows you to modify some of their properties.&#xA;Pre-defined presets (those that are included by default within darktable) are shown with a lock symbol. Their properties cannot be changed.&#xA;User-defined presets can be imported from exported .dtpreset files using the &amp;ldquo;import&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom of the screen. You can export all user-defined presets to a single directory using the &amp;ldquo;export&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lua options</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lua-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lua-options/</guid>
      <description> lua scripts installer don&amp;rsquo;t show again Check this box to hide the lua scripts installer in the lighttable if no lua scripts are installed. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>actions on selection</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/selected-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/selected-image/</guid>
      <description>Perform actions on images that have been selected in the lighttable view.&#xA;🔗module controls The module controls are spread over two tabs for manipulating the image files and the related metadata.&#xA;🔗images tab remove Remove the selected images from the darktable library without deleting them. Removed images can no longer be viewed or edited within darktable but the image files remain on the filesystem along with any XMP sidecar files. As darktable keeps the XMP files up-to-date with your latest development history, you can fully restore your work later by re-importing the images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>camera settings</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/tethering/camera-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/tethering/camera-settings/</guid>
      <description>Set up an image capture job.&#xA;This can include sequence, bracket and delayed captures. You are also able to control other camera settings such as focus mode, aperture, shutter speed, ISO and white balance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>clipping warning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/clipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/clipping/</guid>
      <description>Highlight areas of the image that may exhibit luminance or gamut clipping.&#xA;When an image is sent to a display device, each pixel is normally represented as a set of 3 numbers, representing the intensity of the red, green and blue primary colors in the output color space. Because the output color space is usually closely related to hardware with physical limations, there is a maximum permitted value for the [R,G,B] channels, representing the maximum available intensity for that color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>collection filters</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/</guid>
      <description>Filter the collection of images displayed in the lighttable view and filmstrip panel using image attributes, optionally pinning filters to the top panel for quick access.&#xA;Once you have defined a collection of images with the collections module, the collection filters module allows you to define additional filters and sort criteria. For example, you might wish to show all images in a given folder using the collections module and then define additional quick filters to narrow-down by star rating and/or color label.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>collections</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/</guid>
      <description>Filter the images shown in the lighttable view and filmstrip panel using image attributes. This set of filtered images is known as a collection.&#xA;Importing images into darktable stores information about them (filename, path, Exif data, data from XMP sidecar files etc.) in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database. A collection may be defined by applying filtering rules to these attributes, thus creating a subset of images to display in the lighttable view and the filmstrip module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color assessment</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/color-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/color-assessment/</guid>
      <description>Assess colors and brightness in your image using ISO 12646:2008 recommended viewing conditions.&#xA;When developing an image, the way we perceive brightness, contrast and saturation is influenced by the surrounding ambient conditions. If an image is displayed against a dark background, this can have a number of adverse effects on our perception of that image:&#xA;Exaggeration of the perceived exposure makes the image seems brighter than it really is. This is nicely illustrated by the Adelson checkerboard shadow effect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>duplicate manager</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/duplicate-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/duplicate-manager/</guid>
      <description>View and create multiple versions of the current image. Each version can be edited independently without affecting other versions &amp;ndash; all versions use the same underlying image file, but the editing history of each version is stored in its own independent XMP sidecar file.&#xA;The duplicate manager lists each version of the current darkroom image along with its preview thumbnail. Hold down the left mouse button on a thumbnail to temporarily show that version in the center view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/</guid>
      <description>Export selected images.&#xA;When used in the darkroom view, the currently-edited image will be exported if no other images are selected in the filmstrip.&#xA;Files can be exported to a file on disk, email, various online storage locations, a web album, or a book template.&#xA;🔗module controls 🔗storage options target storage The type of location to store your selected images. A number of different back-ends are implemented, including file on disk, LaTeX book template and various web albums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filmstrip</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/</guid>
      <description>The filmstrip can be used to quickly switch between images. The images shown are the same as those displayed in the lighttable view and are defined by the currently-selected collection.&#xA;The filmstrip can be switched on and off using the shortcut Ctrl+F. The height of the filmstrip panel can be changed by clicking and dragging its top border.&#xA;Quickly navigate through the images in the filmstrip by scrolling with the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>find location</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/</guid>
      <description>Search for a location on the map. You must be connected to the internet to use this feature.&#xA;To use this module, type in a place name or address, press Enter and a list of results will be shown. Click on an item in the list and the map will zoom to that location. An outline covering that location or a pin pointing at the location will be displayed.&#xA;An outline (polygon) can be used to create a user location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>focus peaking</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/</guid>
      <description>Identify which parts of the image contain high contrast details such as edges and textures, which are usually a useful guide to sharpness and therefore focus.&#xA;Activate the module by clicking on the icon. The sharpest parts of the image will be highlighted with a yellow, green and blue overlay:&#xA;Focus peaking works by filtering out most of the image noise, measuring the intensity gradients in the image and calculating average and standard deviation statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gamut check</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/gamut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/gamut/</guid>
      <description>Highlight areas of the image that may exhibit gamut clipping.&#xA;Click the icon to activate the gamut check display mode for your image. This function highlights, in cyan, all pixels that are out of gamut with respect to the selected softproof profile. You can also activate gamut check with the keyboard shortcut Ctrl+G. A message “gamut check” on the bottom left of your image tells you that you are in gamut check display mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>geotagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/geotagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/geotagging/</guid>
      <description>Import and apply GPX track data to a selection of images.&#xA;This module is common to the lighttable and map views. The map view provides an enhanced mode that allows you to preview the position of the images along the GPS tracks while adjusting the images&amp;rsquo; date/time offset and time zone.&#xA;🔗workflow overview A GPS receiver calculates its current position based on information it receives from satellites, and records it in a GPX file together with the current date and time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>global color picker</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/global-color-picker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/global-color-picker/</guid>
      <description>Take color samples from the current darkroom image, display their values in multiple ways and compare colors from different locations.&#xA;The color picker is activated by pressing the color picker icon. The module&amp;rsquo;s parameters will remain in effect until you leave the darkroom mode.&#xA;Besides the global color picker described here, many darktable modules (e.g. tone curve) also contain local color pickers which are used to set individual module parameters. You should be aware that these two forms of color picker do not always work in the same color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>guides &amp; overlays</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/guides-overlays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/guides-overlays/</guid>
      <description>A number of commonly-used compositional guides can be overlaid on your image while you are editing. These can be enabled either globally (all the time) or locally (when certain modules are active).&#xA;Other darkroom functionality also draws colored overlay lines on the image (for example, drawn masks). An option is also provided to change the color of those overlays (see below).&#xA;🔗global guides Left-click the icon in the bottom bar to globally display guide overlays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>history stack</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/history-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/history-stack/</guid>
      <description>View and modify the history stack of the current darkroom image.&#xA;This module lists every change of state (activate/de-activate/move/change parameters) for all processing modules that have been modified for the current image. Select a point in the stack to return to that point in the development history of the image. Shift+click an item in the history stack to expand that module in the right-hand module panel without changing the current edit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>history stack</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/history-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/history-stack/</guid>
      <description>Manipulate the history stack of one or more selected images.&#xA;🔗module controls selective copy&amp;hellip; Copy parts of the history stack from the selected image. A dialog will appear, from which you will be able to select which history stack items you want to copy. For any module, you may also choose to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; that module&amp;rsquo;s parameters &amp;ndash; this will cause the module to be copied but with all controls set to their initial (default) state (as if you had clicked the module reset button).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>image information</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/image-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/image-information/</guid>
      <description>Display information embedded within an image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data as well as a number of additional data fields defined by darktable.&#xA;When hovering with the mouse over image thumbnails, the displayed data is automatically updated to show information about the image currently under the mouse cursor.&#xA;When several images are selected and the focus is not on a single image, the module only displays information that is the same for all images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>image information line</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/image-info-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/image-info-line/</guid>
      <description>Display information about the current image in a darkroom panel.&#xA;The contents of this line can be set in preferences &amp;gt; darkroom. See the variables section for information about the variables that can be used here. You can also insert a newline with $(NL).&#xA;The image information line can be displayed in the top, bottom, left or right panel depending on an additional configuration item in preferences &amp;gt; darkroom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/import/</guid>
      <description>Add images to the darktable library, optionally copying them from another location on the filesystem or from a connected camera.&#xA;See supported file formats for more information.&#xA;🔗module controls The following buttons are shown in the module&amp;rsquo;s UI by default:&#xA;add to library Add existing images to the darktable library without copying or moving files. If you only add a single image to the library it will be automatically loaded in the darkroom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>live view</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/tethering/live-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/tethering/live-view/</guid>
      <description>Control your camera&amp;rsquo;s live view mode.&#xA;Functionality such as focus control, rotation, guides and overlays are supported.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>locations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/locations/</guid>
      <description>Create areas or locations and organize them as hierarchical tags.&#xA;A location is shown as a shape on the map when selected. Initially each location is represented as a square or circle and can be changed to a rectangle or ellipse by adjusting the shape&amp;rsquo;s width and/or height.&#xA;A location can also be created from an OpenStreetMap region (city/country) polygon. To achieve this, first make sure the max polygon points parameter is large enough (some country polygons use more than 150,000 points).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lua scripts installer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/lua-scripts-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/lua-scripts-installer/</guid>
      <description>As described in lua scripts, darktable provides powerful scripting capabilities to extend its functionality and integrate with other software. Many such scripts are already available. The Lua script installer module helps to install them without the need for manual configuration. The first time it is run, instructions are displayed in the module.&#xA;For the module to be able to install the scripts, you will need to have git installed and available on your path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>map settings</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/</guid>
      <description>Select preferred map data from various providers. Some will provide additional layers (satellite view etc.) which you can toggle.&#xA;🔗module controls map source Choose the provider to source map information from. max polygon points The find location module doesn&amp;rsquo;t display polygons with more points than this for performance reasons. Usually a country polygon has between 50,000 and 150,000 points. show OSD Choose whether to display the OSD controls at the top-left of the center view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mask manager</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/mask-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/mask-manager/</guid>
      <description>Manage all drawn masks and shapes for the current image.&#xA;This module can be used to create, rename, edit and delete shapes. You can alter the shapes in a drawn mask, group shapes together, and combine them using set operators.&#xA;The top line of the mask manager panel contains buttons that can be used to create new shapes. These are the same as in the drawn mask interface of the processing modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>metadata editor</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/metadata-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/metadata-editor/</guid>
      <description>Edit the metadata of selected images.&#xA;Metadata is freeformat text (title, description, creator, publisher, rights etc.) that describes your images.&#xA;When several images are selected having different values for a given metadata field, the module displays for that field &amp;ndash; if you choose to apply changes, these fields will not be changed. If you right-click on the field the different values are listed at the end of the contextual menu. Select one of the values in the menu to apply that value to all of the selected images &amp;ndash; the change will be saved once you press the &amp;ldquo;apply&amp;rdquo; button or the Enter/Tab key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>module order</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/module-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/module-order/</guid>
      <description>Change the order of the processing modules in the darkroom using presets.&#xA;When processing an image, the active modules are applied in a specific order, which is shown in the right-hand panel of the darkroom view. This module provides information about the current ordering of the processing modules in the pixelpipe. The name of the currently-selected preset is shown in the module header (or &amp;ldquo;custom&amp;rdquo; if the user has manually modified the order).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>navigation</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/navigation/</guid>
      <description>Zoom and pan the current image.&#xA;The navigation panel (displayed on the top left hand side of the darkroom) shows a full preview of the current image with a rectangle showing the area that is currently visible in the central panel. You can interact with this module using your mouse in the same way as you can interact with the main image (scroll to zoom in/out, middle-click to cycle through zoom levels, click+drag to pan).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>print settings</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/print/print-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/print/print-settings/</guid>
      <description>Manage settings for the print view and initiate printing.&#xA;🔗module controls 🔗printer printer Select one of the installed printers. media The type of media loaded on the printer (Plain Paper, Luster Photo Paper, etc.). profile The printer&amp;rsquo;s ICC profile for the loaded paper. This is the profile specific to the printer and paper. This profile is the last color space transformation applied to the picture whose goal is to create a high quality print.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw overexposed warning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/raw-overexposed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/raw-overexposed/</guid>
      <description>Highlight areas of the image where color channels of the raw input file are clipped.&#xA;Clipped color channels imply an overexposed image with loss of information in the affected areas. Some of this information may be recoverable using the highlight reconstruction, color reconstruction or filmic rgb modules.&#xA;Click on the icon to show/hide the warning overlay. Right-click on the icon to open a dialog containing the following configuration parameters.&#xA;mode Choose how to mark clipped areas: mark with CFA color: Display a pattern of the respective primary colors (red, green, and blue) to indicate which color channels are clipped.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>recently used collections</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/recent-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/recent-collections/</guid>
      <description>Display a list of recently used collections generated by the collections module.&#xA;This module may be hidden, depending on the preferences set in the collections module.&#xA;Click on an entry to reopen the selected collection. This also updates the collections module with the appropriate filter criteria and rules.&#xA;🔗preferences The &amp;ldquo;preferences&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; option in the presets menu allows you to adjust the behavior of the recent collections module as follows:&#xA;number of recent collections to be stored The number of recent collections to store and display in the recent collections module (default 10) prefer a history button in the collections module Set whether you prefer to use this module or the history button in the collections module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scopes</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/</guid>
      <description>This module provides various graphical depictions of the developed image&amp;rsquo;s light levels or chromaticity.&#xA;Hover the mouse over the module to reveal buttons that can be used to adjust the display. The buttons on the left-hand-side are used to choose the display mode, from left-to-right: vectorscope, waveform, rgb parade and histogram. The buttons on the right-hand-side control how the plot for the current scope is drawn.&#xA;The height of the scopes module can be changed by clicking-and-dragging on the bottom edge or by holding down Shift+Alt while scrolling the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>selection</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/select/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/select/</guid>
      <description>Select images in the lighttable according to simple criteria.&#xA;🔗module controls select all Select all images in the current collection. select none De-select all images. invert selection Select all images in the current collection that are not currently selected. select film roll Select all images in the current collection that are in the same film roll as the currently-selected images. select untouched Select all images in the current collection that have not yet been developed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>session</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/tethering/session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/tethering/session/</guid>
      <description>Set a session jobcode to allow the creation of a new film roll.&#xA;A session is a sequence of exposures taken in tethering mode and placed into a single film roll. A new session means the creation of a new film roll.&#xA;The session module allows you to set a jobcode, which can be used to create your new film roll. See preferences &amp;gt; import &amp;gt; session options for details about how to create new film rolls using the $(JOBCODE) variable in the session module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>snapshots</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Store development snapshots and compare with the current edit.&#xA;Snapshots can be taken at any point in the development process and later overlaid onto the current center view. This allows you to undertake a side by side comparison (by default left=snapshot, right=active edit) while you are tuning parameters of a module. It can also be combined with the history stack module to compare a snapshot against different stages of development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>soft proof</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/soft-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/soft-proof/</guid>
      <description>View your image rendered using a selected color profile.&#xA;Click the icon to activate the soft proof display mode on your image. This allows you to preview your image rendered using a printer profile to see how colors will end up on the final print. You can also activate soft proof with the keyboard shortcut Ctrl+S. A message “soft proof&amp;quot; on the bottom left of your image tells you that you are in soft proof display mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>styles</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/</guid>
      <description>Create named styles from selected images&amp;rsquo; history stacks and apply styles to selected images.&#xA;Styles can either be created within this panel or in the history stack module in the darkroom.&#xA;A list of all available styles is displayed in the module. A search field above the list allows you to locate a style by name or description. This module also allows styles to be edited and deleted.&#xA;Double-click on a style name to apply that style to all selected images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/tagging/</guid>
      <description>Manage tags attached to images.&#xA;Tags provide a means of adding information to images using a keyword dictionary. You can also manage tags as a hierarchical tree, which can be useful when their number becomes large.&#xA;Tags are physically stored in XMP sidecar files as well as in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database and can be included in exported images.&#xA;🔗definitions The following definitions assume that you have set up a single tag named &amp;ldquo;places|France|Nord|Lille&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>timeline</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/</guid>
      <description>View your images by the date/time they were taken.&#xA;In the lighttable filemanager view, you can show/hide the timeline module in the bottom panel with the shortcut Ctrl+F.&#xA;Within the timeline, you can show the next and previous dates by scrolling your mouse; Ctrl+scroll to zoom in/out.&#xA;You can also use the timeline to select images by date range by clicking and dragging your mouse.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
