<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lighttable on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lighttable on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>actions on selection</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/selected-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/selected-image/</guid>
      <description>Perform actions on images that have been selected in the lighttable view.&#xA;🔗module controls The module controls are spread over two tabs for manipulating the image files and the related metadata.&#xA;🔗images tab remove Remove the selected images from the darktable library without deleting them. Removed images can no longer be viewed or edited within darktable but the image files remain on the filesystem along with any XMP sidecar files. As darktable keeps the XMP files up-to-date with your latest development history, you can fully restore your work later by re-importing the images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>history stack</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/history-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/history-stack/</guid>
      <description>Manipulate the history stack of one or more selected images.&#xA;🔗module controls selective copy&amp;hellip; Copy parts of the history stack from the selected image. A dialog will appear, from which you will be able to select which history stack items you want to copy. For any module, you may also choose to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; that module&amp;rsquo;s parameters &amp;ndash; this will cause the module to be copied but with all controls set to their initial (default) state (as if you had clicked the module reset button).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/import/</guid>
      <description>Add images to the darktable library, optionally copying them from another location on the filesystem or from a connected camera.&#xA;See supported file formats for more information.&#xA;🔗module controls The following buttons are shown in the module&amp;rsquo;s UI by default:&#xA;add to library Add existing images to the darktable library without copying or moving files. If you only add a single image to the library it will be automatically loaded in the darkroom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lua scripts installer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/lua-scripts-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/lua-scripts-installer/</guid>
      <description>As described in lua scripts, darktable provides powerful scripting capabilities to extend its functionality and integrate with other software. Many such scripts are already available. The Lua script installer module helps to install them without the need for manual configuration. The first time it is run, instructions are displayed in the module.&#xA;For the module to be able to install the scripts, you will need to have git installed and available on your path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>selection</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/select/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/select/</guid>
      <description>Select images in the lighttable according to simple criteria.&#xA;🔗module controls select all Select all images in the current collection. select none De-select all images. invert selection Select all images in the current collection that are not currently selected. select film roll Select all images in the current collection that are in the same film roll as the currently-selected images. select untouched Select all images in the current collection that have not yet been developed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>styles</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/</guid>
      <description>Create named styles from selected images&amp;rsquo; history stacks and apply styles to selected images.&#xA;Styles can either be created within this panel or in the history stack module in the darkroom.&#xA;A list of all available styles is displayed in the module. A search field above the list allows you to locate a style by name or description. This module also allows styles to be edited and deleted.&#xA;Double-click on a style name to apply that style to all selected images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>timeline</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/</guid>
      <description>View your images by the date/time they were taken.&#xA;In the lighttable filemanager view, you can show/hide the timeline module in the bottom panel with the shortcut Ctrl+F.&#xA;Within the timeline, you can show the next and previous dates by scrolling your mouse; Ctrl+scroll to zoom in/out.&#xA;You can also use the timeline to select images by date range by clicking and dragging your mouse.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
