<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lighttable on darktable user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lighttable on darktable user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>actions on selection</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/selected-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/selected-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perform actions on images that have been selected in the lighttable view.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The module controls are spread over two tabs for manipulating the image files and the related metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;images-tab&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#images-tab&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;images tab&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;remove&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Remove the selected images from the darktable library without deleting them. Removed images can no longer be viewed or edited within darktable but the image files remain on the filesystem along with any XMP sidecar files. As darktable keeps the XMP files up-to-date with your latest development history, you can fully restore your work later by re-importing the images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;delete / delete (trash)&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Remove the selected images from the darktable library and remove any associated XMP sidecar files from the filesystem. If no duplicates of a removed image remain in the darktable library, the image file itself is also deleted. You can control whether this action irrevocably deletes the files or attempts to put them into your system&amp;rsquo;s trash bin with a configuration item in &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/security/&#34;&gt;preferences &amp;gt; security&lt;/a&gt;. A second configuration item in the same tab allows you to control whether or not to be prompted before deleting images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;move&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Physically move selected images (the image files plus all associated XMP sidecars) to another folder on the filesystem. If an image with the given filename already exists in the target folder the source image will not be moved.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;copy&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Physically copy selected images (the image file plus all associated XMP sidecars) to another folder on the filesystem. If an image with the given filename already exists in the target folder it will not be overwritten – instead a new duplicate will be generated with the same history stack as the source image.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;create hdr&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Create a high dynamic range image from the selected images, and add the result to the library as a new image in DNG format. Images need to be properly aligned, which implies that they have been taken on a sturdy tripod. You can also generate HDRs with programs like Luminance HDR, and later import them into darktable for further processing. Note that darktable can only create HDR images from raw files.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;duplicate&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Create duplicates of the selected images within darktable. Duplicate images share the same image file, but each duplicate has its own XMP sidecar file and a separate entry in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database. This allows you to test different edits on the same image.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;rotation&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Perform a clockwise or counter-clockwise rotation on the selected images. A third button can be used to reset the image rotation to the value stored in the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data. This feature is directly linked to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/orientation/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;orientation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; processing module &amp;ndash; adjustments made here are automatically converted into a history stack item for that module.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;copy locally&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Create local copies of the selected images on the local drive. These copies will then be used when the original images are not accessible (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/local-copies/&#34;&gt;local copies&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;resync local copy&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Synchronize the XMP sidecar of the local copy of each selected image with the copy in external storage, and remove the local copies. Note that if a local copy has been modified and the external storage is not accessible the local copy will not be deleted (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/local-copies/&#34;&gt;local copies&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;group&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Create a new group from the selected images (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/grouping/&#34;&gt;image grouping&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;ungroup&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Remove the selected images from their group (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/digital-asset-management/grouping/&#34;&gt;image grouping&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;metadata-tab&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#metadata-tab&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;metadata tab&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;metadata type checkboxes&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose the types of metadata (ratings, tags, metadata, colors, geo tags) that you want to operate on.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;copy&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Copy the chosen types of metadata from the selected image onto the clipboard. If you have more than one image selected, or no images selected, then this button is unavailable.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;paste&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Paste any metadata in the clipboard onto the selected images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;clear&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Clear the chosen types of metadata from the selected images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;mode&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;When pasting metadata onto images, this option controls whether the metadata on the clipboard should be merged with the existing metadata (&lt;em&gt;merge&lt;/em&gt;), or should replace it entirely (&lt;em&gt;overwrite&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;refresh exif&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Refresh the Exif data from the source file. Warning: this may overwrite some tags and metadata that you have altered in darktable (such as star ratings).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;monochrome&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Flag the image as monochrome, meaning that it will receive any monochrome-specific workflow treatment that is offered by the processing modules. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/monochrome/&#34;&gt;developing monochrome images&lt;/a&gt; section for more details.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;color&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Remove the monochrome flag from the image so that it will receive the default workflow treatment that is normally used when developing color photos.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>history stack</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/history-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/history-stack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manipulate the history stack of one or more selected images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;selective copy&amp;hellip;&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Copy parts of the history stack from the selected image. A dialog will appear, from which you will be able to select which history stack items you want to copy. For any module, you may also choose to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; that module&amp;rsquo;s parameters &amp;ndash; this will cause the module to be copied but with all controls set to their initial (default) state (as if you had clicked the module reset button).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If more than one image is selected, the history stack is taken from the image that was selected first. Double-click on a history item to copy that item only and immediately close the dialog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/import/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add images to the darktable library, optionally copying them from another location on the filesystem or from a connected camera.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/supported-file-formats/&#34;&gt;supported file formats&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following buttons are shown in the module&amp;rsquo;s UI by default:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#add-to-library&#34;&gt;add to library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Add existing images to the darktable library without copying or moving files. If you only add a single image to the library it will be automatically loaded in the darkroom.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#copy--import&#34;&gt;copy &amp;amp; import&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Create copies of images from the filesystem and then add those copies to the darktable library.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a camera is detected, a new section will appear in the module for that device. If you hover your mouse over the camera label, a tooltip will display information about the camera (model, firmware version etc.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lua scripts installer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/lua-scripts-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/lua-scripts-installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lua/&#34;&gt;lua scripts&lt;/a&gt;, darktable provides powerful scripting capabilities to extend its functionality and integrate with other software. Many such scripts are already available. The Lua script installer module helps to install them without the need for manual configuration. The first time it is run, instructions are displayed in the module.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the module to be able to install the scripts, you will need to have git installed and available on your path. You can get it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git-scm.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>selection</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/select/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/select/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Select images in the lighttable according to simple criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;select all&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Select all images in the current collection.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;select none&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;De-select all images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;invert selection&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Select all images in the current collection that are not currently selected.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;select film roll&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Select all images in the current collection that are in the same film roll as the currently-selected images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;select untouched&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Select all images in the current collection that have not yet been developed.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>styles</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Create named styles from selected images&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/pixelpipe/history-stack/&#34;&gt;history stacks&lt;/a&gt; and apply styles to selected images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Styles can either be created within this panel or in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/history-stack/&#34;&gt;history stack&lt;/a&gt; module in the darkroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A list of all available styles is displayed in the module. A search field above the list allows you to locate a style by name or description. This module also allows styles to be edited and deleted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Double-click on a style name to apply that style to all selected images.  A style may also be applied to all selected images by pressing a shortcut key assigned to it (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/shortcuts/&#34;&gt;preferences &amp;gt; shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;) while in the lighttable or darkroom view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>timeline</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;View your images by the date/time they were taken.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/timeline.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/timeline/timeline.png&#34; alt=&#34;timeline&#34;   /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the lighttable filemanager view, you can show/hide the timeline module in the bottom panel with the shortcut Ctrl+F.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within the timeline, you can show the next and previous dates by scrolling your mouse; Ctrl+scroll to zoom in/out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also use the timeline to select images by date range by clicking and dragging your mouse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
