<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>darkroom on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in darkroom on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>clipping warning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/clipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/clipping/</guid>
      <description>Highlight areas of the image that may exhibit luminance or gamut clipping.&#xA;When an image is sent to a display device, each pixel is normally represented as a set of 3 numbers, representing the intensity of the red, green and blue primary colors in the output color space. Because the output color space is usually closely related to hardware with physical limations, there is a maximum permitted value for the [R,G,B] channels, representing the maximum available intensity for that color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color assessment</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/color-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/color-assessment/</guid>
      <description>Assess colors and brightness in your image using ISO 12646:2008 recommended viewing conditions.&#xA;When developing an image, the way we perceive brightness, contrast and saturation is influenced by the surrounding ambient conditions. If an image is displayed against a dark background, this can have a number of adverse effects on our perception of that image:&#xA;Exaggeration of the perceived exposure makes the image seems brighter than it really is. This is nicely illustrated by the Adelson checkerboard shadow effect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>duplicate manager</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/duplicate-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/duplicate-manager/</guid>
      <description>View and create multiple versions of the current image. Each version can be edited independently without affecting other versions &amp;ndash; all versions use the same underlying image file, but the editing history of each version is stored in its own independent XMP sidecar file.&#xA;The duplicate manager lists each version of the current darkroom image along with its preview thumbnail. Hold down the left mouse button on a thumbnail to temporarily show that version in the center view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gamut check</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/gamut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/gamut/</guid>
      <description>Highlight areas of the image that may exhibit gamut clipping.&#xA;Click the icon to activate the gamut check display mode for your image. This function highlights, in cyan, all pixels that are out of gamut with respect to the selected softproof profile. You can also activate gamut check with the keyboard shortcut Ctrl+G. A message “gamut check” on the bottom left of your image tells you that you are in gamut check display mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>global color picker</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/global-color-picker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/global-color-picker/</guid>
      <description>Take color samples from the current darkroom image, display their values in multiple ways and compare colors from different locations.&#xA;The color picker is activated by pressing the color picker icon. The module&amp;rsquo;s parameters will remain in effect until you leave the darkroom mode.&#xA;Besides the global color picker described here, many darktable modules (e.g. tone curve) also contain local color pickers which are used to set individual module parameters. You should be aware that these two forms of color picker do not always work in the same color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>guides &amp; overlays</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/guides-overlays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/guides-overlays/</guid>
      <description>A number of commonly-used compositional guides can be overlaid on your image while you are editing. These can be enabled either globally (all the time) or locally (when certain modules are active).&#xA;Other darkroom functionality also draws colored overlay lines on the image (for example, drawn masks). An option is also provided to change the color of those overlays (see below).&#xA;🔗global guides Left-click the icon in the bottom bar to globally display guide overlays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>history stack</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/history-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/history-stack/</guid>
      <description>View and modify the history stack of the current darkroom image.&#xA;This module lists every change of state (activate/de-activate/move/change parameters) for all processing modules that have been modified for the current image. Select a point in the stack to return to that point in the development history of the image. Shift+click an item in the history stack to expand that module in the right-hand module panel without changing the current edit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>image information line</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/image-info-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/image-info-line/</guid>
      <description>Display information about the current image in a darkroom panel.&#xA;The contents of this line can be set in preferences &amp;gt; darkroom. See the variables section for information about the variables that can be used here. You can also insert a newline with $(NL).&#xA;The image information line can be displayed in the top, bottom, left or right panel depending on an additional configuration item in preferences &amp;gt; darkroom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mask manager</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/mask-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/mask-manager/</guid>
      <description>Manage all drawn masks and shapes for the current image.&#xA;This module can be used to create, rename, edit and delete shapes. You can alter the shapes in a drawn mask, group shapes together, and combine them using set operators.&#xA;The top line of the mask manager panel contains buttons that can be used to create new shapes. These are the same as in the drawn mask interface of the processing modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>module order</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/module-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/module-order/</guid>
      <description>Change the order of the processing modules in the darkroom using presets.&#xA;When processing an image, the active modules are applied in a specific order, which is shown in the right-hand panel of the darkroom view. This module provides information about the current ordering of the processing modules in the pixelpipe. The name of the currently-selected preset is shown in the module header (or &amp;ldquo;custom&amp;rdquo; if the user has manually modified the order).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>navigation</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/navigation/</guid>
      <description>Zoom and pan the current image.&#xA;The navigation panel (displayed on the top left hand side of the darkroom) shows a full preview of the current image with a rectangle showing the area that is currently visible in the central panel. You can interact with this module using your mouse in the same way as you can interact with the main image (scroll to zoom in/out, middle-click to cycle through zoom levels, click+drag to pan).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw overexposed warning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/raw-overexposed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/raw-overexposed/</guid>
      <description>Highlight areas of the image where color channels of the raw input file are clipped.&#xA;Clipped color channels imply an overexposed image with loss of information in the affected areas. Some of this information may be recoverable using the highlight reconstruction, color reconstruction or filmic rgb modules.&#xA;Click on the icon to show/hide the warning overlay. Right-click on the icon to open a dialog containing the following configuration parameters.&#xA;mode Choose how to mark clipped areas: mark with CFA color: Display a pattern of the respective primary colors (red, green, and blue) to indicate which color channels are clipped.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>snapshots</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Store development snapshots and compare with the current edit.&#xA;Snapshots can be taken at any point in the development process and later overlaid onto the current center view. This allows you to undertake a side by side comparison (by default left=snapshot, right=active edit) while you are tuning parameters of a module. It can also be combined with the history stack module to compare a snapshot against different stages of development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>soft proof</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/soft-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/darkroom/soft-proof/</guid>
      <description>View your image rendered using a selected color profile.&#xA;Click the icon to activate the soft proof display mode on your image. This allows you to preview your image rendered using a printer profile to see how colors will end up on the final print. You can also activate soft proof with the keyboard shortcut Ctrl+S. A message “soft proof&amp;quot; on the bottom left of your image tells you that you are in soft proof display mode.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
