<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lighttable on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lighttable on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/overview/</guid>
      <description>The lighttable view allows you to view and manage your image collection.&#xA;The centre view contains thumbnails of your images &amp;ndash; how they are displayed depends on which mode you are working in.&#xA;While the mouse is over an image thumbnail or images are selected, there are a number of actions you can perform with keyboard shortcuts:&#xA;F1, F2, F3, F4, F5 adds or removes a color label (red, yellow, green, blue, purple, respectively).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lighttable view layout</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-view-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/lighttable-view-layout/</guid>
      <description>🔗left panel From top to bottom:&#xA;import Import images from the filesystem or a connected camera. collections Filter the images displayed in the lighttable center panel &amp;ndash; also used to control the images displayed in the filmstrip and timeline modules. recently used collections View recently used collections of images. image information Display image information. lua scripts installer (optional) Install lua scripts. 🔗right panel From top to bottom:&#xA;selection Select images in the lighttable using simple criteria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>undo/redo</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/undo-redo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/undo-redo/</guid>
      <description>Most changes made within the lighttable are recorded and can be reverted to a previous state. This includes modifications to color labels, ratings, geo-localization, tags, metadata, orientation, copy/paste of history, image duplication, or application of a style. Note that the facility to undo/redo actions is unlimited in the number of steps while in the lighttable view, but it is reset each time you switch to a different view.&#xA;Press Ctrl+Z to undo the last modification and Ctrl+Y to redo the last undone modification (if any).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
