<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>masking &amp; blending on darktable user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/</link>
    <description>Recent content in masking &amp; blending on darktable user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each processing module takes its input from the preceding module in the pixelpipe, performs its operation on the image data, and then hands the output to the next module in the pixelpipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A module&amp;rsquo;s output data can optionally be reprocessed (combined) with its input data before being handed to the next module. This additional processing step is called &lt;em&gt;blending&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; input and output data is reprocessed using algorithms called blending operators or &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/blend-modes/&#34;&gt;blend modes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blend modes</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/blend-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/masking-and-blending/blend-modes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blend modes define how the input and output of a module are combined (blended) together before the module&amp;rsquo;s final output is passed to the next module in the pixelpipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Classic blending modes, designed for display-referred RGB (constrained to 0-100%), implicitly define a fulcrum at 50% (gray) or 100% (white) in their algorithms, depending on the blend mode. Because scene-referred is not subject to these restrictions, this fulcrum needs to be explicitly defined by the user when performing blending operations in the &amp;ldquo;RGB (scene)&amp;rdquo; color space. The additional &lt;em&gt;blend fulcrum&lt;/em&gt; parameter will be presented to the user when using one of these blend modes in this color space. The effect depends on the operator used. For example, values above the fulcrum might be brightened and values below darkened, or vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
