<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>processing modules on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in processing modules on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>astrophoto denoise</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/astrophoto-denoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/astrophoto-denoise/</guid>
      <description>Remove image noise while preserving structure.&#xA;This is accomplished by averaging each pixel with some surrounding pixels in the image. The weight of such a pixel in the averaging process depends on the similarity of its neighborhood with the neighborhood of the pixel being denoised. A patch with a defined size is used to measure that similarity.&#xA;As denoising is a resource-intensive process, it slows down pixelpipe processing significantly. Consider activating this module late in your workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>base curve</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/base-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/base-curve/</guid>
      <description>Simulate the in-camera JPEG by applying a characteristic base curve to the image.&#xA;darktable comes with a number of base curve presets that attempt to mimic the curves of various camera manufacturers. These presets are automatically applied according to the manufacturer ID found in the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data. Camera-specific base curve presets are also available for some camera models.&#xA;This module will be enabled by default if preferences &amp;gt; processing &amp;gt; auto-apply pixel workflow defaults is set to &amp;ldquo;display-referred&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bloom</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/bloom/</guid>
      <description>Create a soft bloom effect.&#xA;This module works by blurring the highlights and then blending the result with the original image.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, and is no longer recommended. Instead, use the tone equalizer module or the exposure module with a parametric mask.&#xA;🔗module controls size The spatial extent of the bloom effect. threshold The threshold for the brightness increase. strength The strength of the overlighting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blurs</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/blurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/blurs/</guid>
      <description>Simulate physically-accurate blurs in scene-referred RGB space.&#xA;🔗blur types Three types of blur are provided:&#xA;lens blur: Simulates a lens diaphragm with a configurable number of blades and blade curvature to create synthetic bokeh. motion blur: Simulates the effect of camera motion with a configurable path. gaussian blur: This is not really an optical blur but can be used for denoising or for creative effects using blend modes A diagram at the top of the module shows the shape of the blurring operator (known as the point spread function).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>censorize</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/censorize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/censorize/</guid>
      <description>Degrade parts of the image in an aesthetically pleasing way, in order to anonymize people/objects or hide body parts.&#xA;Censorize works in linear RGB color space to apply a physically-accurate gaussian blur and gaussian luminance noise.&#xA;Aside from anonymization, this module can also be used for a wide range of creative purposes, for example:&#xA;Combine a simple blur with a multiply blend mode to create a realistic bloom (Orton effect). Combine a simple blur with a subtract blending mode and low opacity to create an unsharp mask, similar to the sharpen module but in an RGB scene-referred space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chromatic aberrations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/chromatic-aberrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/chromatic-aberrations/</guid>
      <description>Correct chromatic aberrations.&#xA;In contrast to the raw chromatic aberrations module, this module does not require raw data as input.&#xA;🔗workflow To obtain the best result, you are advised to proceed as follows:&#xA;Attenuate the chromatic aberrations as much as possible in the lens correction module using the TCA sliders. Increase the strength slider in this module to better see its effect. Increase the radius until the chromatic aberrations disappear. If this is insufficient, try enabling the &amp;ldquo;very large chromatic aberrations&amp;rdquo; setting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color balance</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance/</guid>
      <description>A versatile tool for adjusting the image&amp;rsquo;s color balance.&#xA;This module can be used to revert parasitic color casts or to enhance the visual atmosphere of an image using color grading, a popular technique in the cinema industry. For scene-referred workflow, you should consider using the improved color balance rgb module instead.&#xA;🔗overview The color balance module allows you to shift colors selectively by luminance range (shadows, mid-tones, and highlights). It can do this using two different methods:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color balance rgb</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance-rgb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-balance-rgb/</guid>
      <description>An advanced module which brings color-grading tools from cinematography into the photographic scene-referred pipeline.&#xA;This module is not suitable for beginners with no prior knowledge of color theory, who might want to stick to the global chroma and global vibrance settings until they have a good understanding of the dimensions of color.&#xA;🔗introduction Color-grading is an important part of image editing. It can help to remove unwanted color casts and can also deliver a creative color twist that will add atmosphere to your images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color calibration</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-calibration/</guid>
      <description>A fully-featured color-space correction, white balance adjustment and channel mixer module.&#xA;This simple yet powerful module can be used in the following ways:&#xA;To adjust the white balance (chromatic adaptation), working in tandem with the white balance module. Here, the white balance module makes some initial adjustments (required for the demosaic module to work effectively), and the color calibration module then calculates a more perceptually-accurate white balance after the input color profile has been applied.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color contrast</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-contrast/</guid>
      <description>A simplified control for changing the contrast or separation of colors between the green/magenta and blue/yellow axes in Lab color space. Higher values increase color contrast, lower values decrease it.&#xA;🔗module controls green-magenta contrast Change the green-magenta color contrast. This is equivalent to raising or lowering the steepness of the a* curve in Lab. Lower values desaturate greens and magenta, while higher values increase their saturation. blue-yellow contrast Change the blue-yellow color contrast.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color correction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-correction/</guid>
      <description>Modify the global image saturation to give the image a tint or as an alternative method to split-tone the image.&#xA;Note: Use the color balance rgb module for color modifications.&#xA;🔗module controls color board For split toning move the white dot to the desired highlight tint and then select a tint for shadows with the dark spot. For a simple global tint set both spots to the same color. saturation Correct the global saturation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color equalizer (placeholder)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-equalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-equalizer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color look up table</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-look-up-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-look-up-table/</guid>
      <description>A generic color look up table implemented in Lab space.&#xA;The input to this module is a list of source and target points and the complete mapping is interpolated using splines. The resulting look up tables (LUTs) are editable by hand and can be created using the darktable-chart utility to match given input (such as hald-cluts and RAW/JPEG with in-camera processing pairs). See using darktable-chart for details.&#xA;🔗module controls color board The color board grid shows a list of colored patches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color mapping</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Transfer the look and feel of one image to another.&#xA;This module statistically analyses the color characteristics of a source and target image. The colors of the source image are then mapped to corresponding colors on the target image.&#xA;Two steps are required to use this module:&#xA;Open the source image in the darkroom view and acquire its color characteristics by pressing the “acquire as source” button. A set of color clusters is generated and displayed in the “source clusters” area.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>Recover color information in blown-out highlights.&#xA;Due to the nature of digital sensors, overexposed highlights lack valid color information. Most frequently they appear neutral white or exhibit some color cast, depending on what other image processing steps are involved. This module can be used to “heal” overexposed highlights by replacing their colors with better fitting ones. The module acts on pixels whose luminance exceeds a user-defined threshold. Replacement colors are taken from neighboring pixels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>color zones</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/color-zones/</guid>
      <description>Selectively adjust the lightness, chroma and hue of pixels based on their current lightness, chroma and hue.&#xA;This module works in CIE LCh color space, which separates pixels into lightness, chroma and hue components. It allows you to manipulate the lightness, chroma and hue of targeted groups of pixels through the use of curves.&#xA;You first need to choose whether you wish to adjust (select) pixels based on their lightness, chroma or hue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>colorize</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/colorize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/colorize/</guid>
      <description>Add a solid layer of color to the image.&#xA;🔗module controls hue The hue of the color layer. saturation The saturation of shadow tones. lightness The lightness of the color layer. source mix Controls how the lightness of the input image is mixed with the color layer. Setting this to zero will result in a uniformly colored plane. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>composite (placeholder)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/composite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/composite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contrast equalizer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-equalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-equalizer/</guid>
      <description>Adjust luminance and chroma contrast in the wavelet domain.&#xA;This versatile module can be used to achieve a variety of effects, including bloom, denoise, clarity, and local contrast enhancement.&#xA;It works in the wavelet domain and its parameters can be tuned independently for each wavelet detail scale. The module operates in CIE LCh color space and so is able to treat luminosity and chromaticity independently.&#xA;A number of presets are provided, which should help you to understand the capabilities of the module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>crop</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop/</guid>
      <description>Crop an image using on-screen guides.&#xA;This module appears later in the pipeline than the deprecated crop and rotate module, meaning that the full image can remain available for source spots in the retouch module. For best results, you are advised to use the rotate and perspective module to perform rotation and perspective correction (if required), and then perform final creative cropping with this module.&#xA;Whenever this module is in focus, the full uncropped image will be shown, overlaid with crop handles and optional guiding lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>demosaic</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/demosaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/demosaic/</guid>
      <description>Control how raw files are demosaiced.&#xA;🔗bayer filters The sensor cells of a digital camera are not color-sensitive &amp;ndash; they are only able to record different levels of lightness. In order to obtain a color image, each cell is covered by a color filter (red, green or blue) that primarily passes light of that color. This means that each pixel of the raw image only contains information about a single color channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>denoise (profiled)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/denoise-profiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/denoise-profiled/</guid>
      <description>An easy to use and highly efficient denoise module, adapted to the individual noise profiles of a wide range of camera sensors.&#xA;One issue with a lot of denoising algorithms is that they assume that the variance of the noise is independent of the luminosity of the signal. By profiling the noise characteristics of a camera&amp;rsquo;s sensor at different ISO settings, the variance at different luminosities can be assessed, and the denoising algorithm can be adjusted to more evenly smooth out the noise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>diffuse or sharpen</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/diffuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/diffuse/</guid>
      <description>Diffusion is a family of physical processes by which particles move and spread gradually with time, from a source that generates them. In image processing, diffusion mostly occurs in two places:&#xA;diffusion of photons through lens glass (blur) or humid air (hazing), diffusion of pigments in wet inks or watercolors. In both cases, diffusion makes the image less sharp by &amp;ldquo;leaking&amp;rdquo; particles and smoothing local variations.&#xA;The diffuse or sharpen module uses a generalized physical model to describe several kinds of diffusion, and can be used by image makers to either simulate or revert diffusion processes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dither or posterize</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/dither-or-posterize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/dither-or-posterize/</guid>
      <description>This module eliminates some of the banding artifacts that can result when darktable&amp;rsquo;s internal 32-bit floating point data is transferred into discrete 8-bit or 16-bit integer output format for display or export. It can also be used for creative posterization effects.&#xA;Although not an inherent problem in any of darktable&amp;rsquo;s modules, some operations may provoke banding if they produce a lightness gradient in the image. To mitigate possible artifacts you should consider activating dithering when using the vignetting or graduated density modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>enlarge canvas (placeholder)</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/enlarge-canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/enlarge-canvas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>exposure</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/exposure/</guid>
      <description>Increase or decrease the overall brightness of an image.&#xA;This module has two modes of operation:&#xA;manual Set the exposure and black level manually automatic (RAW images only) Use an analysis of the image&amp;rsquo;s histogram to automatically set the exposure. Darktable automatically selects the exposure compensation that is required to shift the selected percentile to the selected target level (see definitions below). This mode is particularly useful for automatically altering a large number of images to have the same exposure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filmic rgb</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/filmic-rgb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/filmic-rgb/</guid>
      <description>Remap the tonal range of an image by reproducing the tone and color response of classic film.&#xA;This module can be used either to expand or to contract the dynamic range of the scene to fit the dynamic range of the display. It protects colors and contrast in the mid-tones, recovers the shadows, and compresses bright highlights and dark shadows. Highlights will need extra care when details need to be preserved (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>framing</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/framing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/framing/</guid>
      <description>Generate a frame around the image.&#xA;The frame consists of a border (with a user-defined color) and a frame line within that border (with a second user-defined color). Various options are available to control the geometry and color of the frame.&#xA;🔗module controls border size The size of the frame as a percentage of the underlying full image. aspect The aspect ratio of the final module output (i.e. the underlying image plus the frame).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>graduated density</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/graduated-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/graduated-density/</guid>
      <description>Simulate a graduated density filter in order to correct exposure and color in a progressive manner.&#xA;A line is shown on screen allowing the position and rotation of the gradient to be modified with the mouse.&#xA;This module is known to provoke banding artifacts under certain conditions. You should consider activating the dither or posterize module to alleviate these issues.&#xA;🔗module controls density Set the density of the filter (EV). A low value underexposes slightly whereas a high value creates a strong filter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>grain</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/grain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/grain/</guid>
      <description>Simulate the grain of analog film. The grain is processed on the L channel of Lab color space.&#xA;🔗module controls coarseness The grain size, scaled to simulate an ISO number. strength The strength of the effect. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>haze removal</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/haze-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/haze-removal/</guid>
      <description>Automatically reduce the effect of dust and haze in the atmosphere. This module may also be employed more generally to give pictures a color boost specifically in low-contrast regions of the image.&#xA;Haze absorbs light from objects in the scene but it is also a source of diffuse background light. The haze removal module first estimates, for each image region, the amount of haze in the scene. It then removes the diffuse background light according to its local strength and recovers the original object light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>highlight reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highlight-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highlight-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>Attempt to reconstruct color information for pixels that are clipped in one or more RGB channel.&#xA;🔗clipping Clipping occurs when the amount of captured light exceeds either the capacity of a camera&amp;rsquo;s sensor to record that light (photosite saturation) or the capacity of the Raw file to store it (digital clipping). Once a pixel is clipped we can no longer know the precise brightness of that pixel &amp;ndash; only that it is equal to or greater than the maximum value that pixel can store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>highpass</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highpass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/highpass/</guid>
      <description>A high pass filter.&#xA;This module is primarily intended to be used in combination with a blend mode. For example, try using the module with a blend mode of &amp;ldquo;soft light&amp;rdquo; for high pass sharpening.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can result in undesirable effects, and is no longer recommended. Instead, use the contrast equalizer module for fine sharpness or the local contrast module for general sharpness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hot pixels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/hot-pixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/hot-pixels/</guid>
      <description>Automatically detect and eliminate hot pixels.&#xA;Hot pixels are pixels which have failed to record a light level correctly. Detected hot pixels are replaced by an average of their neighbors.&#xA;🔗module controls threshold How strong a pixel&amp;rsquo;s value needs to deviate from that of its neighbors to be regarded as a hot pixel. strength The blending strength of the hot pixels with their surrounding. detect by 3 neighbours Extend the detection of hot pixels &amp;ndash; regard a pixel as hot if a minimum of only three (instead of four) neighbor pixels deviate by more than the threshold level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>input color profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/input-color-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/input-color-profile/</guid>
      <description>Define how darktable will interpret the colors of the image.&#xA;This module takes the color space used by the image source (e.g. camera, scanner) and converts the pixel encodings to a standardized working color space. This means that subsequent modules in the pipeline don&amp;rsquo;t need to be concerned with the specifics of the input device, and can work with and convert to/from a common working color space.&#xA;Where an image has been captured in a raw file, the input color profile module will normally apply either a standard or enhanced color matrix specific for that camera model, which will be used to map the colors into the working profile color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lens correction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lens-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lens-correction/</guid>
      <description>Automatically correct for (or simulate) lens distortion, transverse chromatic aberrations (TCA) and vignetting.&#xA;You can choose to either use lens correction data embedded in your Raw file (where present/supported) or correction data provided by the external Lensfun library.&#xA;Additional controls are also provided for manual vignetting correction, in case the profiles for your lens are insufficient or missing.&#xA;Note that if TCA correction is enabled in this module, also using raw chromatic aberrations may cause artifacts from over-correction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>liquify</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/liquify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/liquify/</guid>
      <description>Move pixels around by applying freestyle distortions to parts of the image using points, lines and curves.&#xA;As you might want to use source data from any part of the image you will be shown the uncropped image (possibly with the cropping rectangle overlaid as a guide) while the module is active.&#xA;🔗nodes Each of liquify&amp;rsquo;s tools is based on nodes. A point consists of a single node and a line or curve consists of a sequence of linked nodes defining a path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>local contrast</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/local-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/local-contrast/</guid>
      <description>Enhance the image&amp;rsquo;s local contrast.&#xA;This is achieved using either a local laplacian (default) or unnormalized bilateral filter. Both modes work exclusively on the L channel from Lab. The local laplacian filter has been designed to be robust against unwanted halo effects and gradient reversals along edges.&#xA;🔗module controls mode Choice of local laplacian filter or bilateral grid. The following sections define the controls available for each of these modes. 🔗bilateral grid coarseness Adjust the coarseness of the details to be adjusted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lowlight vision</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowlight-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowlight-vision/</guid>
      <description>Simulate human lowlight vision. This module can also be used to perform a day-to-night conversion.&#xA;The idea is to calculate a scotopic vision image, which is perceived by the rods rather than the cones in the eyes under low light. Scotopic lightness is then mixed with photopic value (regular color image pixel) using some blending function. This module can also simulate the Purkinje effect by adding some blueness to the dark parts of the image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lowpass</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowpass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lowpass/</guid>
      <description>Apply a low pass filter (for example, a Gaussian blur) to the image, while controlling the output contrast and saturation.&#xA;This module is primarily intended to be used in combination with a blend mode. For example, try using the local contrast mask preset with the overlay blend mode.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can produce undesirable effects, and is no longer recommended. Instead, use the contrast equalizer module for blurring or the tone equalizer module for dynamic range compression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUT 3D</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lut-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/lut-3d/</guid>
      <description>Transform RGB values with a 3D LUT file.&#xA;A 3D LUT is a tridimensional table that is used to transform a given RGB value into another RGB value. It is normally used for film simulation and color grading.&#xA;This module accepts .cube, .3dl, .png (haldclut) and .gmz files. Uncompressed 3D LUT data is not saved in the database or the XMP file, but is instead saved to the 3D LUT file path inside the 3D LUT root folder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>monochrome</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/monochrome/</guid>
      <description>Quickly convert an image to black &amp;amp; white using a variable color filter.&#xA;To use this module, first reduce the filter size (to concentrate its effect) and move it across the hue palette to find the best filter value for your desired image rendition. Then gradually expand the filter to include more hues and achieve more natural tonality.&#xA;Although this module is easy to use, better results can usually be obtained by using the film emulation presets in the color calibration module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>negadoctor</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/negadoctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/negadoctor/</guid>
      <description>Process scanned film negatives.&#xA;You can obtain an image of a negative using a film scanner, or by photographing it against a white light (e.g. a light table or computer monitor) or off-camera flash.&#xA;🔗preparation If the image of the negative was obtained using a digital camera, then in order to obtain accurate colors in the final image, you will need to take the following points into consideration:&#xA;When taking the photograph, adjust the exposure to fully utilise the entire dynamic range of your camera sensor &amp;ndash; i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>orientation</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/orientation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/orientation/</guid>
      <description>Rotate the image 90 degrees at a time or flip the image horizontally and/or vertically.&#xA;The module is enabled by default and the orientation (rotation) is automatically set based on the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data.&#xA;The orientation can also be set using the actions on selection module in the lighttable view.&#xA;🔗module controls transform Double click the label to reset to the default transformations rotate counter-clockwise Rotate the image 90 degrees counter-clockwise rotate clockwise Rotate the image 90 degrees clockwise flip horizontally Flip the image (mirror) horizontally flip vertically Flip the image (mirror) vertically show guides Tick the box to show guide overlays whenever the module is activated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>output color profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/output-color-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/output-color-profile/</guid>
      <description>Manage the output profile for export and the rendering intent to be used when mapping between color spaces.&#xA;darktable comes with pre-defined profiles sRGB, Adobe RGB, XYZ and linear RGB. You can provide additional profiles by placing them in $DARKTABLE/share/darktable/color/out and $HOME/.config/darktable/color/out (where $DARKTABLE is the darktable installation directory and $HOME is your home directory). Note that these color/out directories are not created by the darktable install; if you need to use one, you must create it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw black/white point</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-black-white-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-black-white-point/</guid>
      <description>Define camera-specific black and white points.&#xA;This module is activated automatically for all raw images. Default settings are applied for all supported cameras. Changes to the defaults are not normally required.&#xA;🔗module controls black level 0-3 The camera-specific black level of the four pixels in the RGGB Bayer pattern. Pixels with values lower than this level are not considered to contain valid data. white point The camera-specific white level. All pixels with values above this are likely to be clipped and will be handled accordingly in the highlight reconstruction module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw chromatic aberrations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-chromatic-aberrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-chromatic-aberrations/</guid>
      <description>Correct chromatic aberrations of raw images.&#xA;This module currently only works for raw images recorded with a Bayer sensor (the sensor used in the majority of cameras) &amp;ndash; for other types of image, you should use the chromatic aberrations module instead.&#xA;The module will also not apply any corrections to any photos that have been identified as monochrome (see developing monochrome images for more information).&#xA;This module expects good white balance data (provided by the white balance module) for best results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>raw denoise</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-denoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/raw-denoise/</guid>
      <description>Perform denoising on raw image data before it is demosaiced.&#xA;This module has been ported from dcraw.&#xA;🔗module controls noise threshold The threshold for noise detection. Higher values lead to stronger noise removal and greater loss of image detail. coarse/fine curves The noise of an image is usually a combination of fine-grained and coarse-grained noise. These curves allow the image to be denoised more or less depending on the coarseness of the visible noise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>retouch</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/retouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/retouch/</guid>
      <description>Remove unwanted elements from your image by cloning, healing, blurring and filling using drawn shapes.&#xA;This module extends the capabilities of the deprecated spot removal module (equivalent to this module&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;clone&amp;rdquo; tool) by including a &amp;ldquo;heal&amp;rdquo; tool (based on the heal tool from GIMP), as well as &amp;ldquo;fill&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;blur&amp;rdquo; modes. It can also take advantage of wavelet decomposition, allowing the image to be separated into layers of varying detail (from coarse to fine) which can be selectively retouched before being recombined to produce the output image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rgb curve</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-curve/</guid>
      <description>A classic digital photography tool to alter an image&amp;rsquo;s tones using curves.&#xA;This module is very similar to the tone curve module but works in RGB color space.&#xA;Activate the color picker on the left to show the picked values in the graph (Ctrl+click or right-click to use the picker in area mode). Numerical (Lab) values of the input and output (see below) at the selected spot or area are shown at the top left of the widget.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rgb levels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-levels/</guid>
      <description>Adjust black, white and mid-gray points in RGB color space. This module is silmilar to the levels module, which works in Lab color space.&#xA;The rgb levels tool shows a histogram of the image, and displays three bars with handles. Drag the handles to modify the black, middle-gray and white points in lightness (in &amp;ldquo;RGB, linked channels&amp;rdquo; mode) or independently for each of the R, G and B channels (in &amp;ldquo;RGB, independent channels&amp;rdquo; mode).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rgb primaries</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-primaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rgb-primaries/</guid>
      <description>Adjust the hue and purity of the RGB primary colors (i.e. which red, green and blue they represent), while leaving uncolored (gray) pixels unchanged. In addition to preserving gray pixels, the opponency relationships between the colors are also preserved under this adjustment: If you increase the purity of the blue primary, the opponent yellow&amp;rsquo;s intensity increases to balance things out; If you twist the blue hue toward cyan, the opponent yellow is twisted toward orange.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rotate and perspective</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Automatically correct for converging lines, a form of perspective distortion. The underlying mechanism is inspired by Markus Hebel&amp;rsquo;s ShiftN program. This module also allows for the rotation of the image to be adjusted.&#xA;Perspective distortions are a natural effect when projecting a three dimensional scene onto a two dimensional plane and cause objects close to the viewer to appear larger than objects further away. Converging lines are a special case of perspective distortions frequently seen in architectural photographs &amp;ndash; parallel lines, when photographed at an angle, are transformed into converging lines that meet at some vantage point within or outside of the image frame.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rotate pixels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-pixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/rotate-pixels/</guid>
      <description>The sensors of some cameras (such as the Fujifilm FinePix S2Pro, F700, and E550) have a diagonally oriented Bayer pattern instead of the usual orthogonal layout.&#xA;Without correction this would lead to a tilted image with black corners. This module applies the required rotation.&#xA;darktable detects images that need correction using their Exif data and automatically activates this module where required. For other images the module always remains disabled.&#xA;The module has no controls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scale pixels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/scale-pixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/scale-pixels/</guid>
      <description>Some cameras (such as the Nikon D1X) have rectangular instead of the usual square sensor cells. Without correction this would lead to distorted images. This module applies the required scaling.&#xA;darktable detects images that need correction using their Exif data and automatically activates this module where required. For other images the module always remains disabled.&#xA;The module has no controls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shadows and highlights</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/shadows-and-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/shadows-and-highlights/</guid>
      <description>Modify the tonal range of the shadows and highlights of an image by enhancing local contrast.&#xA;Note: This module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can result in a number of issues when the parameters are pushed hard, including halos, high local contrast in highlights, and hue shifts towards blue in the shadows. You are advised to use the tone equalizer module instead.&#xA;🔗module controls shadows Control the effect on shadows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sharpen</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sharpen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sharpen/</guid>
      <description>Sharpen the details in the image using a standard UnSharp Mask (USM).&#xA;This module works by increasing the contrast around edges and thereby enhancing the impression of sharpness of an image. This module is applied to the L channel in Lab color space.&#xA;Note: The USM algorithm used in this module performs blurs in Lab color space, which can produce undesirable effects, and is no longer recommended. Instead use the presets offered by the contrast equalizer module for deblurring or the local contrast module for general sharpness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sigmoid</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sigmoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/sigmoid/</guid>
      <description>Remap the tonal range of an image using a modified generalized log-logistic curve.&#xA;This module can be used to expand or contract the dynamic range of the scene to fit the dynamic range of the display.&#xA;Note: Modules placed before sigmoid in the pipeline operate in scene-referred space. Modules after sigmoid work in display-referred space.&#xA;🔗usage Please take note of the following guidelines while using this module within your workflow:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>soften</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/soften/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/soften/</guid>
      <description>Create a softened image using the Orton effect.&#xA;Michael Orton achieved his results on slide film by using two exposures of the same scene, one well exposed and one overexposed. He then used a darkroom technique to blend these two images into a final image where the overexposed image was blurred.&#xA;This module is a near-copy of Orton&amp;rsquo;s analog process into the digital domain.&#xA;🔗module controls size The size of blur of the overexposed image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>split-toning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/split-toning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/split-toning/</guid>
      <description>Create a two color linear toning effect where the shadows and highlights are represented by two different colors.&#xA;The split-toning module does not convert images to black and white and has limited benefits on color images. In order to perform traditional split-toning, the input to this module should therefore be monochrome.&#xA;🔗module controls shadows and highlights color Set the desired hue and saturation for both shadows and highlights. Clicking on the colored squares will open a color selector dialog which offers you a choice of commonly used colors, or allows you to define a color in RGB color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>surface blur</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/surface-blur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/surface-blur/</guid>
      <description>Smooth image surfaces while preserving sharp edges using a bilateral filter.&#xA;This module can be used to denoise images, however you should be aware that bilateral filters are susceptible to overshoots and darktable offers much better alternatives. For example, the astrophoto denoise module uses a non-local means denoising algorithm, and the denoise (profiled) module provides a choice between non-local means and wavelet denoising algorithms.&#xA;The surface blur module blurs noise within the surfaces of an image by averaging pixels with their neighbors, taking into account not only their geometric distance but also their distance on the range scale (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tone curve</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-curve/</guid>
      <description>A classic digital photography tool to alter the tones of an image&amp;rsquo;s using curves.&#xA;This module is very similar to the rgb curve module but works in Lab color space.&#xA;Activate the color picker to show the picked values on the displayed histogram (Ctrl+click or right-click to use the picker in area mode). Numerical (Lab) values of the input and output (see below) at the selected spot or area are shown at the top left of the graph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tone equalizer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-equalizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-equalizer/</guid>
      <description>Dodge and burn while preserving local contrast.&#xA;When used together with filmic rgb, this module replaces the need for other tone-mapping modules such as the base curve, shadows and highlights, tone curve and zone system (deprecated) modules. It works in linear RGB space and utilizes a user-defined mask to guide the dodging and burning adjustments, helping to preserve local contrast within the image.&#xA;The following diagram describes how the tone equalizer works:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>unbreak input profile</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/unbreak-input-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/unbreak-input-profile/</guid>
      <description>Add a correction curve to image data. This is required if you have selected certain input profiles in the input color profile module.&#xA;If you decide to use an ICC profile from the camera manufacturer in the input color profile module, a correction curve frequently needs to be pre-applied to image data to prevent the final output from looking too dark. This extra processing is not required if you use darktable&amp;rsquo;s standard or enhanced color matrices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velvia</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/velvia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/velvia/</guid>
      <description>Resaturate pixels in a weighted manner that gives more weight to blacks, whites and less saturated pixels.&#xA;Note: This module causes hue and brightness shifts that can be difficult to manage. Instead, use the color balance rgb module for color modifications.&#xA;🔗module controls strength The strength of the effect mid-tones bias Reduce the effect on mid-tones in order to avoid unnatural skin tones. Reducing the mid-tone bias decreases mid-tone protection and makes the overall velvia effect stronger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vignetting</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vignetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vignetting/</guid>
      <description>Apply a vignetting effect to the image.&#xA;Vignetting is a modification of the brightness and saturation at the borders of the image in a specified shape. Many of the parameters listed below can also be modified with a graphical control that overlays the image when the module has focus, showing the shape and extent of the effect.&#xA;Note: This module is known to provoke banding artifacts under certain conditions. You should consider activating the dither or posterize module to alleviate this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>watermark</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/watermark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/watermark/</guid>
      <description>Render a vector-based overlay onto your image. Watermarks are standard SVG documents and can be designed using Inkscape.&#xA;You can also use bitmap (PNG) images.&#xA;The SVG processor in darktable can also substitute strings within an SVG document, allowing image-dependent information to be included in the watermark.&#xA;User-designed watermarks should be placed into the directory $HOME/.config/darktable/watermarks. Once in place, use the reload button update the list of available watermarks.&#xA;The following is a list of variable strings that are supported for substitution within an SVG document.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>white balance</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/white-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/white-balance/</guid>
      <description>Adjust the white balance of the image by altering the temperature and tint, defining a coefficient for each RGB channel, or choosing from list of predefined white balance settings.&#xA;The default settings for this module are derived from the camera white balance stored in the image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data.&#xA;White balance is not intended as a &amp;ldquo;creative&amp;rdquo; module &amp;ndash; its primary goal is to technically correct the white balance of the image ensuring that neutral colored objects in the scene are rendered with neutral colors in the image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) basic adjustments</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/basic-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/basic-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the quick access panel instead.&#xA;A convenience module that combines controls from exposure, highlight reconstruction, color balance and vibrance into a single module.&#xA;While this module can provide a quick and convenient way to make simple adjustments to an image, it must be used with care. Normally exposure adjustments should come before input color profile in the pixelpipe, and color adjustments should come after.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) channel mixer</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/channel-mixer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/channel-mixer/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the color calibration module instead.&#xA;A simple yet powerful tool to manage color channels.&#xA;This module accepts red, green and blue channels as an input and provides red, green, blue, gray, hue, saturation and lightness channels as output. It allows you to independently control how much each input channel contributes to each output channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) contrast brightness saturation</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-brightness-saturation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/contrast-brightness-saturation/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 4.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the color balance rgb module instead.&#xA;A very basic tool for adjusting the contrast, brightness and saturation of an image. Please note that a number of other modules provide much more versatile methods of adjusting these parameters.&#xA;All module controls default to a neutral position (zero) and provide the ability to increase or decrease the relevant parameter</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) crop and rotate</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop-rotate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/crop-rotate/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.8 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the crop module to crop the image, the rotate and perspective module to perform rotation and keystone correction, and the orientation module to flip the image on the horizontal/vertical axes.&#xA;Crop, rotate, and correct perspective distortions using on-screen guides.&#xA;Whenever the user interface of this module is in focus, the full uncropped image will be shown, overlaid with crop handles and optional guiding lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) defringe</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/defringe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/defringe/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the chromatic aberrations module instead.&#xA;Remove color fringing, which often results from Longitudinal Chromatic Aberrations (LCA), also known as Axial Chromatic Aberrations.&#xA;This module uses edge-detection. Where pixels are detected as a fringe, the color is rebuilt from less saturated neighboring pixels.&#xA;🔗module controls operation mode global average: This mode is usually the fastest but might show slightly incorrect previews at high magnification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) fill light</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/fill-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/fill-light/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the tone equalizer module or the exposure module with a drawn mask.&#xA;Locally modify exposure based on pixel lightness.&#xA;This module pushes exposure by increasing lightness with a Gaussian curve of a specified width, centered on a given lightness.&#xA;🔗module controls exposure The fill-light exposure (EV) center The median lightness impacted by the fill-light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) global tonemap</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/global-tonemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/global-tonemap/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the filmic rgb module instead.&#xA;Compress the tonal range of an HDR image into the limited tonal range of a typical LDR output file.&#xA;Global tonemap processes each pixel of an HDR image, without taking the local surrounding into account. This is generally faster than local tone mapping (deprecated), but might lead to less convincing results with very high-dynamic-range scenes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) invert</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/invert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/invert/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the negadoctor module instead.&#xA;Invert scanned negatives.&#xA;🔗module controls color of film material Clicking on the colored field will open a color selector dialog which offers you a choice of commonly used colors, or allows you to define an RGB color. You can also activate the color picker to take a color probe from your image – preferably from the unexposed border of your negative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) levels</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/levels/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 4.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the rgb levels module instead.&#xA;Adjust black, white and mid-gray points.&#xA;The levels tool offers two modes of operation:&#xA;manual The levels tool shows a histogram of the image, and displays three bars with handles. Drag the handles to modify the black, middle-gray and white points in absolute values of image lightness (the L value from Lab).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) spot removal</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/spot-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/spot-removal/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the &amp;ldquo;cloning&amp;rdquo; tool in the retouch module instead.&#xA;Correct areas of an image (the target) using details from another area of the image (the source).&#xA;This module uses some of the shapes that are available for drawn masks (circles, ellipses and paths), and the user interface is similar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) tone mapping</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/tone-mapping/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the tone equalizer module instead.&#xA;Compress the tonal range of HDR images so that they fit into the limits of an LDR image, using Durand&amp;rsquo;s 2002 algorithm.&#xA;The underlying algorithm uses a bilateral filter to decompose an image into a coarse base layer and a detail layer. The contrast of the base layer is compressed, while the detail layer is preserved, then both layers are re-combined.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) vibrance</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vibrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/vibrance/</guid>
      <description> Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.6 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the vibrance control in the color balance rgb module instead.&#xA;Saturate and reduce the lightness of the most saturated pixels to make the colors more vivid.&#xA;🔗module controls vibrance The amount of vibrance to apply to the image. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(deprecated) zone system</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/zone-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/zone-system/</guid>
      <description>Please note that this module is deprecated from darktable 3.4 and should no longer be used for new edits. Please use the tone equalizer or multiple instances of the exposure module with parametric masks to narrow down on a zone.&#xA;Adjust the lightness of an image using Ansel Adams&amp;rsquo; zone system.&#xA;The lightness of the image (the L channel in Lab color space) is divided into a number of zones ranging from pure black to pure white.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
