<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preferences &amp; Settings on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preferences &amp; Settings on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/overview/</guid>
      <description>darktable comes with a number of user-configurable preferences. These can be adjusted in the preferences dialog, which can be reached by clicking the gear icon on the right of the top panel. Preferences are separated into tabs, each of which is described in more detail in the following sections.&#xA;When opened from within the lighttable or darkroom views, the appropriate tab will be loaded by default to allow you to modify that view&amp;rsquo;s settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>general</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/general/</guid>
      <description>Control the overall look and feel of darktable.&#xA;interface language Set the language of the user interface. The system default is marked with an * (needs a restart) theme Set the theme for the user interface. Aside from any aesthetic considerations, the recommended interface color for color evaluation is middle gray. Visual perception is affected by ambient brightness, and a low user interface brightness causes all kinds of illusions. Using a dark interface to retouch photos can therefore lead to excessive retouching (abuse of contrast and saturation) and to a photo that is too dark when printed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/import/</guid>
      <description>Control default file naming conventions used when importing images.&#xA;🔗session options The following options define the default naming pattern for use in the &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; import&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; import from camera&amp;rdquo; options in the import module, or when taking photos in the tethering view.&#xA;The naming pattern consists of three parts: a base part defining the parent folder, a session part defining a sub directory (which is specific to the individual import session), and a file name part defining the filename structure for each imported image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lighttable</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lighttable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lighttable/</guid>
      <description>Control functionality in the lighttable view and modules.&#xA;🔗general hide built-in presets for utility modules If enabled, only user-defined presets will be shown in presets menu for utility modules &amp;ndash; built-in presets will be hidden (default off). use single-click in the collections module Enable &amp;ldquo;single click&amp;rdquo; mode in the collections module, which allows ranges to be selected (default off). expand a single utility module at a time Controls how utility modules are expanded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darkroom</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/darkroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/darkroom/</guid>
      <description>Control functionality in the darkroom view and associated modules.&#xA;🔗general scroll down to increase mask parameters By default, scrolling your mouse up increases the value of the relevant shape parameters in drawn masks. Set this preference to reverse the behavior (default off). middle mouse button zooms to 200% When enabled, clicking the middle mouse button on the image canvas causes the zoom level to toggle between fit, 100% and 200%. When disabled, the middle mouse button toggles between fit and 100%.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>processing</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/processing/</guid>
      <description>Control how images are processed.&#xA;🔗image processing always use LittleCMS 2 to apply output color profile If this option is activated, darktable will use the LittleCMS 2 system library to apply the output color profile instead of its own internal routines. This is significantly slower than the default but might give more accurate results in some cases. If the given ICC is LUT-based or contains both a LUT and a matrix, darktable will use LittleCMS 2 to render the colors regardless of this parameter&amp;rsquo;s value (default off).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>security</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/security/</guid>
      <description>Control whether warning messages are shown before undertaking certain activities.&#xA;🔗general ask before removing images from the library Always ask before removing image information from darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database, where the xmp file is retained (default on). ask before deleting images from disk Always ask before deleting an image file (default on). ask before discarding history stack Always ask before discarding the history stack of an image (default on). try to use trash when deleting images Instead of physically deleting images from disk, attempt to put them into the system&amp;rsquo;s trash bin (default on).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>storage</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/storage/</guid>
      <description>The following options are related to darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database and XMP sidecar files.&#xA;🔗database create database snapshot Specifies how often darktable should create database snapshots. Options are &amp;ldquo;never&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;once a month&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;once a week&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;once a day&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;on close&amp;rdquo; (default &amp;ldquo;once a week&amp;rdquo;) how many snapshots to keep Number of snapshots to keep after creating a new snapshot, not counting database backups taken when moving between darktable versions. Enter &amp;ldquo;-1&amp;rdquo; to store an unlimited number of snapshots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>miscellaneous</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description>🔗interface load default shortcuts at startup When launching the application, darktable loads default shortcuts first, and then loads user-defined shortcuts on top. This allows default shortcuts to be overridden with a new action but prevents them from being deleted (since the deleted shortcut will be automatically reloaded on the next restart). Deactivate this preference to stop loading default shortcuts on startup &amp;ndash; only load the user-defined ones (including any defaults that you have not subsequently deleted or overridden).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>You can perform almost any action in darktable with a keyboard/mouse shortcut. You can also use various other input devices, including MIDI devices and game controllers &amp;ndash; see the midi device support section for details. These are referred to as external devices or just devices in this guide.&#xA;🔗defining shortcuts A shortcut is a combination of key or button presses and/or mouse or device movements that performs an action in darktable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>presets</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/presets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/presets/</guid>
      <description>This menu provides an overview of the presets that are defined for darktable&amp;rsquo;s modules, and allows you to modify some of their properties.&#xA;Pre-defined presets (those that are included by default within darktable) are shown with a lock symbol. Their properties cannot be changed.&#xA;User-defined presets can be imported from exported .dtpreset files using the &amp;ldquo;import&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom of the screen. You can export all user-defined presets to a single directory using the &amp;ldquo;export&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lua options</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lua-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/lua-options/</guid>
      <description> lua scripts installer don&amp;rsquo;t show again Check this box to hide the lua scripts installer in the lighttable if no lua scripts are installed. </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
