<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>an introduction to darktable&#39;s workflow on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in an introduction to darktable&#39;s workflow on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>introduction</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/introduction/</guid>
      <description>This section is intended to provide you with a flavor of what darktable can do and offer a suggested end-to-end processing workflow. New users should start by working through this introduction and following the links provided for further details.&#xA;Please note that this is not an exhaustive guide and many useful topics are not covered. You are advised to read through the reference sections of this manual once you are familiar with the basics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>import &amp; review</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/import-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/import-review/</guid>
      <description>Before you can do anything in darktable you must first add some images files to the library using the import module in the lighttable view. This will create entries for your images in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database so that it can keep track of the changes you make. There are three ways to import images, each accessible through buttons in the import module:&#xA;add to library This option adds images to the library without copying or moving &amp;ndash; your original files will stay in their current location and will not be altered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>process</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/process/</guid>
      <description>This section is intended to get you comfortable processing images in the darkroom view using a scene-referred workflow. You are advised to follow the guidelines provided below, up to the end of the image processing in 3 modules section and then choose other areas to learn as-and-when you need to use those techniques in your images.&#xA;🔗getting started 🔗take a well-exposed photograph Good image processing techniques start in the camera &amp;ndash; a well-exposed image (without blown highlights or heavily crushed blacks) will always make post-processing much more straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/workflow/export/</guid>
      <description>darktable is a non-destructive editor, which means that all changes are recorded in the library database (with a backup stored in an XMP sidecar file), and the original Raw file is left untouched. You therefore need to export images in order to bake your edits into an output file that can be distributed outside of darktable.&#xA;Choose an export scenario.&#xA;The export module offers many options, but by far the most common use is to “save a developed raw image as a JPEG”.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
