<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>organization on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in organization on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/overview/</guid>
      <description>Processing modules are organized and accessed via the right-hand panel in the darkroom:&#xA;Click on the icons at the top of this panel to reveal, from left to right,&#xA;quick access panel A customizable panel allowing quick access to commonly-used module controls. active modules A group containing the modules that are currently active in the pixelpipe. Right-click to show all modules that are present in the history stack within the active group, regardless of whether or not they are actually active.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>module groups</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/module-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/module-groups/</guid>
      <description>A number of pre-defined module groups are shipped with darktable and are selectable as presets. These are summarized below.&#xA;All of these presets (with the exception of modules: deprecated and search only) also include the quick access panel. All except the modules: deprecated group include the search bar.&#xA;🔗modules: all This preset contains all modules, sorted according to the traditional module groupings used prior to darktable 3.4, as follows:&#xA;base modules The minimal set of modules normally required to render a presentable image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>quick access panel</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/quick-access-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/quick-access-panel/</guid>
      <description>The quick access panel allows you to access widgets from a number of processing modules all in one place.&#xA;You can add new widgets to the panel by&#xA;right-clicking on the &amp;ldquo;hamburger&amp;rdquo; icon at the top-left of the panel using the manage module layouts screen Ctrl+clicking on a widget in a processing module while in visual shortcut mapping mode Click on the icon to the right of the module name to open the full version of that module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>manage module layouts</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/manage-module-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/organization/manage-module-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Manage the layout and grouping of processing modules and the quick access panel.&#xA;This maintenance screen can be accessed from the presets menu beside the module search box or module group icons (below the scopes module in the darkroom view). Ctrl+click on the preset menu to open this screen directly.&#xA;Settings are automatically saved when you exit the screen. Click reset to abandon any changes made in the current editing session.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
