<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shared on darktable user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/</link>
    <description>Recent content in shared on darktable user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>collection filters</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filter the &lt;em&gt;collection&lt;/em&gt; of images displayed in the lighttable view and filmstrip panel using image attributes, optionally pinning filters to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/user-interface/top-panel/&#34;&gt;top panel&lt;/a&gt; for quick access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have defined a &lt;em&gt;collection&lt;/em&gt; of images with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/&#34;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt; module, the collection filters module allows you to define additional filters and sort criteria. For example, you might wish to show all images in a given folder using the collections module and then define additional quick filters to narrow-down by star rating and/or color label.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>collections</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filter the images shown in the lighttable view and filmstrip panel using image attributes. This set of filtered images is known as a &lt;em&gt;collection&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Importing images into darktable stores information about them (filename, path, Exif data, data from XMP sidecar files etc.) in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database. A collection may be defined by applying filtering rules to these attributes, thus creating a subset of images to display in the lighttable view and the filmstrip module.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Export selected images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When used in the darkroom view, the currently-edited image will be exported if no other images are selected in the filmstrip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Files can be exported to a file on disk, email, various online storage locations, a web album, or a book template.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;storage-options&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#storage-options&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;storage options&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;target storage&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The type of location to store your selected images. A number of different back-ends are implemented, including file on disk, LaTeX book template and various web albums. Depending on the selected target, you will be asked to provide additional information, such as filenames or account name and password.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;filename template&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Define the folder and file to which the image will be exported. This can be automatically generated using several pre-defined variables. For example, &lt;code&gt;$(SEQUENCE)&lt;/code&gt; in a template records sequence number of the image exported to the target. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/variables/&#34;&gt;variables&lt;/a&gt; section for details.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;output directory selector&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The button beside the filename template entry opens a dialog to select the parent directory for export.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;on conflict&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose what to do if the generated filename conflicts with an existing file on export:&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;create unique filename&lt;/em&gt;: Automatically choose a unique new file name by appending an integer to name of the conflicting file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;overwrite&lt;/em&gt;: Automatically overwrite existing files. This option will present you with a confirmation dialog in order to protect you from accidental data loss &amp;ndash; you can disable this in &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/preferences-settings/security/&#34;&gt;preferences &amp;gt; security &amp;gt; ask before exporting in overwrite mode&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This dialog is not presented per-file but as a one-off confirmation before the export job starts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;overwrite if changed&lt;/em&gt;: Automatically overwrite existing files if the last export timestamp stored in darktable&amp;rsquo;s database does not match the last changed date/time on the existing file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;skip&lt;/em&gt;: Do not export images where the destination filename already exists.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;format-options&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#format-options&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;format options&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;file format&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose the file format for the exported image. Additional options will appear (below) depending on the selected format.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;quality&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The quality of the exported file. Higher values lead to larger file sizes. The default quality (95) is a good setting for very high quality exports (e.g. for archiving or printing purposes). If you need a good compromise between size and quality (e.g. for online image display or uploads) you should consider a value of “90” instead.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;bit depth&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The number of bits used for each color channel. More bits means less posterization/color banding.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;compression&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The type of compression to use.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;compression level&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;For export formats where &lt;em&gt;compression&lt;/em&gt; can be specified, the &lt;em&gt;compression level&lt;/em&gt; specifies how much compression to apply. The higher the level, the more the data will be compressed, at the cost of more CPU cycles.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;b&amp;amp;w image&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;For TIFF export format, it is possible to save a monochrome image. This setting controls whether the resulting file encodes the shades of gray as separate RGB channels, or as a single grayscale channel. The latter option will result in smaller files.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-options&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#global-options&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;global options&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;set size&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose how to measure the maximum size of your exported image&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;in pixels (for file)&lt;/em&gt;: Enter the maximum width and height in pixels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;in cm (for print)&lt;/em&gt;: Enter the maximum width and height in cm and define the image&amp;rsquo;s dpi. The equivalent size in pixels will be automatically calculated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;in inch (for print)&lt;/em&gt;: Enter the maximum width and height in inches and define the image&amp;rsquo;s dpi. The equivalent size in pixels will be automatically calculated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;by scale (for file)&lt;/em&gt;: Enter a multiplier to specify by how much the exported image should be scaled compared to the input image. For example, entering a value of 0.5 will result in an output image with half the width and height (in pixels) of the original image.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;dpi&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;If units of cm or inches are chosen, set the dpi of the output image. The dpi will also be stored in the Exif data of the exported image. It will be automatically set to 300 if &amp;ldquo;in pixels&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;by scale&amp;rdquo; is chosen.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;max size&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Set the maximum width and height of the exported image(s) in pixels, cm or inches (depending on the selected unit) &amp;ndash; zero means that no constraint will be set on that dimension. Exported images will be constrained so as not to exceed either of these values, while retaining the correct aspect ratio. Set both to zero to export with the original dimensions (after cropping). If the entered values exceed the original dimensions darktable will either export with the original dimensions or upscale the image, depending on the &amp;ldquo;allow upscaling&amp;rdquo; parameter.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;allow upscaling&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Set to “yes” to perform an upscaling step if the user-defined maximum width and height exceed the original dimensions of the image. If set to “no” the exported image&amp;rsquo;s dimensions will not exceed the dimensions of the original image (after cropping).&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;high quality resampling&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Set this to &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to perform high quality resampling on the image. The image will be processed in full resolution and only downscaled at the very end. This can sometimes result in better quality, but will always be slower.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;store masks&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Store masks as additional layers (for TIFF format) or channels (for EXR and XCF formats) in the exported image.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;profile&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The output color profile. Select “image settings” if you want the settings in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/processing-modules/output-color-profile/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;output color profile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; module of the individual images to be respected.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;intent&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;This option lets you define the intent &amp;ndash; the way in which darktable will handle out-of-gamut colors. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/rendering-intent/&#34;&gt;rendering intent&lt;/a&gt; for a more detailed description of the available options.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;style&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose a &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/lighttable/styles/&#34;&gt;style&lt;/a&gt; which darktable will combine with the existing history stack to generate the output image. These history items are only added temporarily &amp;ndash; the original history stack is not overwritten. You can use this feature to add processing steps and parameters that you want to be applied specifically to images before export. For example you may define a style that adds a stronger level of sharpening when you produce scaled-down JPEG files for the internet or add a certain level of exposure compensation to all of your output images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;mode&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;When applying a style during export this option defines whether the history stack items of that style replace the original history stack of the image or are appended to it. Technically speaking, in append mode history stack items of the style will constitute separate instances of the respective modules on top of any existing ones (see also &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/darkroom/processing-modules/multiple-instances/&#34;&gt;multiple instances&lt;/a&gt;). As a consequence the original history stack will remain in effect with the new items being applied in addition. This way you can apply an overall adjustment (e.g. exposure) to a number of exported images while respecting the settings of each individual image.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;start export&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Press this button to start a background job to export all selected images. A bar at the bottom of the left hand panel displays the progress of the export job. Furthermore a notification message pops up reporting the completion of each individual export. You may click on the pop-up to make it disappear. You may abort the export job by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;x&amp;rdquo; icon located close to the progress bar.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;multi-preset export&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Expanding this section allows you to easily export each of the selected images with several different presets in a single export run. For example, you may wish to export each image in multiple sizes at the same time for use in a website. Simply create a preset for each type of export you wish to make, ensuring that the file path settings for each preset is unique (so that the exported images don&amp;rsquo;t overwrite one another). Select the desired presets and press the &amp;ldquo;start export&amp;rdquo; button as normal.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Images that are selected but currently hidden (because they are members of a collapsed group) will not be exported.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filmstrip</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The filmstrip can be used to quickly switch between images. The images shown are the same as those displayed in the lighttable view and are defined by the currently-selected collection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/filmstrip.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/filmstrip.png&#34; alt=&#34;filmstrip&#34;   /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The filmstrip can be switched on and off using the shortcut Ctrl+F. The height of the filmstrip panel can be changed by clicking and dragging its top border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quickly navigate through the images in the filmstrip by scrolling with the mouse. Increase scroll speed with Shift+scroll. Change the height of the filmstrip with Ctrl+scroll or by clicking+dragging the top of the panel. Change the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/#custom-sort&#34;&gt;custom sort&lt;/a&gt; order of images by dragging and dropping image thumbnails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>focus peaking</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identify which parts of the image contain high contrast details such as edges and textures, which are usually a useful guide to sharpness and therefore focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Activate the module by clicking on the &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/focus-peaking-icon.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/focus-peaking-icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;focus-peaking-icon&#34;  class=&#34;icon&#34;    /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA; icon. The sharpest parts of the image will be highlighted with a yellow, green and blue overlay:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Focus peaking works by filtering out most of the image noise, measuring the intensity gradients in the image and calculating average and standard deviation statistics. When the gradient of an edge differs significantly from the mean, the associated pixels are marked with a &amp;ldquo;heat map&amp;rdquo; indicating how sharp the edge is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>geotagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/geotagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/geotagging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Import and apply GPX track data to a selection of images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This module is common to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/lighttable/&#34;&gt;lighttable&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/map/&#34;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; views. The map view provides an enhanced mode that allows you to preview the position of the images along the GPS tracks while adjusting the images&amp;rsquo; date/time offset and time zone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;workflow-overview&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#workflow-overview&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;workflow overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A GPS receiver calculates its current position based on information it receives from satellites, and records it in a GPX file together with the current date and time. The Exif data of the images also contains a time stamp defined by the camera settings. The &lt;em&gt;geotagging&lt;/em&gt; module takes the time stamp of the image, looks up the position in the GPX file at that time, and stores the appropriate coordinates (latitude/longitude/elevation) in its database and the image&amp;rsquo;s XMP sidecar file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>image information</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/image-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/image-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Display information embedded within an image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data as well as a number of additional data fields defined by darktable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When hovering with the mouse over image thumbnails, the displayed data is automatically updated to show information about the image currently under the mouse cursor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When several images are selected and the focus is not on a single image, the module only displays information that is the same for all images. If any fields differ between the images, the text &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;various values&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; is displayed instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>metadata editor</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/metadata-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/metadata-editor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edit the metadata of selected images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metadata is freeformat text (title, description, creator, publisher, rights etc.) that describes your images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;reset&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Delete visible metadata (see below) from the selected images.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;metadata entry fields&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;A separate entry field is displayed for each visible metadata item, containing its current value (if any). Press Ctrl+Enter to insert a new line in a field. Double-click on a field&amp;rsquo;s label to delete the contents of that field.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When several images are selected that have differing values for a given field, the module displays &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;leave unchanged&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; for that field &amp;ndash; if you choose to apply changes, these fields will not be changed. If you right-click on such a field, the different values are listed at the end of the contextual menu. Select one of those values to apply that value to all of the selected images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>recently used collections</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/recent-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/recent-collections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Display a list of recently used collections generated by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/&#34;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click on an entry to reopen the selected collection. This also updates the collections module with the appropriate filter criteria and rules.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preferences&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#preferences&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;preferences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;preferences&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; option in the presets menu allows you to adjust the behavior of the recent collections module as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;number of recent collections to be stored&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The number of recent collections to store and display in the recent collections module (default 10)&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;prefer a history button in the collections module&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Set whether you prefer to use this module or the history button in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/&#34;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scopes</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This module provides various graphical depictions of the developed image&amp;rsquo;s light levels or &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-management/color-dimensions/#definitions&#34;&gt;chromaticity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/scopes.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/scopes.png&#34; alt=&#34;scopes module&#34;  class=&#34;w50&#34;    /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hover the mouse over the module to reveal buttons that can be used to adjust the display. The buttons on the left-hand-side are used to choose the display mode, from left-to-right: vectorscope, waveform, rgb parade and histogram. The buttons on the right-hand-side control how the plot for the current scope is drawn.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The height of the scopes module can be changed by clicking-and-dragging on the bottom edge or by holding down Shift+Alt while scrolling the mouse. The visibility of the module can be toggled with a keyboard shortcut (default Ctrl+Shift+H).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/tagging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manage tags attached to images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tags provide a means of adding information to images using a keyword dictionary. You can also manage tags as a hierarchical tree, which can be useful when their number becomes large.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tags are physically stored in &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/overview/sidecar-files/&#34;&gt;XMP sidecar files&lt;/a&gt; as well as in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database and can be included in &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/&#34;&gt;exported&lt;/a&gt; images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;definitions&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#definitions&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;definitions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following definitions assume that you have set up a single tag named &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;places|France|Nord|Lille&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
