<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shared on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/</link>
    <description>Recent content in shared on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>collection filters</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collection-filters/</guid>
      <description>Filter the collection of images displayed in the lighttable view and filmstrip panel using image attributes, optionally pinning filters to the top panel for quick access.&#xA;Once you have defined a collection of images with the collections module, the collection filters module allows you to define additional filters and sort criteria. For example, you might wish to show all images in a given folder using the collections module and then define additional quick filters to narrow-down by star rating and/or color label.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>collections</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/collections/</guid>
      <description>Filter the images shown in the lighttable view and filmstrip panel using image attributes. This set of filtered images is known as a collection.&#xA;Importing images into darktable stores information about them (filename, path, Exif data, data from XMP sidecar files etc.) in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database. A collection may be defined by applying filtering rules to these attributes, thus creating a subset of images to display in the lighttable view and the filmstrip module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>export</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/export/</guid>
      <description>Export selected images.&#xA;When used in the darkroom view, the currently-edited image will be exported if no other images are selected in the filmstrip.&#xA;Files can be exported to a file on disk, email, various online storage locations, a web album, or a book template.&#xA;🔗module controls 🔗storage options target storage The type of location to store your selected images. A number of different back-ends are implemented, including file on disk, LaTeX book template and various web albums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>filmstrip</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/filmstrip/</guid>
      <description>The filmstrip can be used to quickly switch between images. The images shown are the same as those displayed in the lighttable view and are defined by the currently-selected collection.&#xA;The filmstrip can be switched on and off using the shortcut Ctrl+F. The height of the filmstrip panel can be changed by clicking and dragging its top border.&#xA;Quickly navigate through the images in the filmstrip by scrolling with the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>focus peaking</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/focus-peaking/</guid>
      <description>Identify which parts of the image contain high contrast details such as edges and textures, which are usually a useful guide to sharpness and therefore focus.&#xA;Activate the module by clicking on the icon. The sharpest parts of the image will be highlighted with a yellow, green and blue overlay:&#xA;Focus peaking works by filtering out most of the image noise, measuring the intensity gradients in the image and calculating average and standard deviation statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>geotagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/geotagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/geotagging/</guid>
      <description>Import and apply GPX track data to a selection of images.&#xA;This module is common to the lighttable and map views. The map view provides an enhanced mode that allows you to preview the position of the images along the GPS tracks while adjusting the images&amp;rsquo; date/time offset and time zone.&#xA;🔗workflow overview A GPS receiver calculates its current position based on information it receives from satellites, and records it in a GPX file together with the current date and time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>image information</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/image-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/image-information/</guid>
      <description>Display information embedded within an image&amp;rsquo;s Exif data as well as a number of additional data fields defined by darktable.&#xA;When hovering with the mouse over image thumbnails, the displayed data is automatically updated to show information about the image currently under the mouse cursor.&#xA;When several images are selected and the focus is not on a single image, the module only displays information that is the same for all images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>metadata editor</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/metadata-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/metadata-editor/</guid>
      <description>Edit the metadata of selected images.&#xA;Metadata is freeformat text (title, description, creator, publisher, rights etc.) that describes your images.&#xA;When several images are selected having different values for a given metadata field, the module displays for that field &amp;ndash; if you choose to apply changes, these fields will not be changed. If you right-click on the field the different values are listed at the end of the contextual menu. Select one of the values in the menu to apply that value to all of the selected images &amp;ndash; the change will be saved once you press the &amp;ldquo;apply&amp;rdquo; button or the Enter/Tab key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>recently used collections</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/recent-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/recent-collections/</guid>
      <description>Display a list of recently used collections generated by the collections module.&#xA;This module may be hidden, depending on the preferences set in the collections module.&#xA;Click on an entry to reopen the selected collection. This also updates the collections module with the appropriate filter criteria and rules.&#xA;🔗preferences The &amp;ldquo;preferences&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; option in the presets menu allows you to adjust the behavior of the recent collections module as follows:&#xA;number of recent collections to be stored The number of recent collections to store and display in the recent collections module (default 10) prefer a history button in the collections module Set whether you prefer to use this module or the history button in the collections module.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scopes</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/scopes/</guid>
      <description>This module provides various graphical depictions of the developed image&amp;rsquo;s light levels or chromaticity.&#xA;Hover the mouse over the module to reveal buttons that can be used to adjust the display. The buttons on the left-hand-side are used to choose the display mode, from left-to-right: vectorscope, waveform, rgb parade and histogram. The buttons on the right-hand-side control how the plot for the current scope is drawn.&#xA;The height of the scopes module can be changed by clicking-and-dragging on the bottom edge or by holding down Shift+Alt while scrolling the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tagging</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/shared/tagging/</guid>
      <description>Manage tags attached to images.&#xA;Tags provide a means of adding information to images using a keyword dictionary. You can also manage tags as a hierarchical tree, which can be useful when their number becomes large.&#xA;Tags are physically stored in XMP sidecar files as well as in darktable&amp;rsquo;s library database and can be included in exported images.&#xA;🔗definitions The following definitions assume that you have set up a single tag named &amp;ldquo;places|France|Nord|Lille&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
