<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>map on darktable user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/</link>
    <description>Recent content in map on darktable user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>find location</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Search for a location on the map. You must be connected to the internet to use this feature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use this module, type in a place name or address, press Enter and a list of results will be shown. Click on an item in the list and the map will zoom to that location. An outline covering that location or a pin pointing at the location will be displayed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An outline (polygon) can be used to create a user location. Check the &lt;em&gt;max polygon points&lt;/em&gt; parameter in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/&#34;&gt;map settings&lt;/a&gt; module to ensure that sufficient points are available for a polygon to be displayed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>locations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/locations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Create areas or locations and organize them as hierarchical tags.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A location is shown as a shape on the map when selected. Initially each location is represented as a square or circle and can be changed to a rectangle or ellipse by adjusting the shape&amp;rsquo;s width and/or height.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A location can also be created from an OpenStreetMap region (city/country) polygon. To achieve this, first make sure the &lt;em&gt;max polygon points&lt;/em&gt; parameter is large enough (some country polygons use more than 150,000 points). Then select the desired location in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/&#34;&gt;find location&lt;/a&gt; module. When the corresponding region shape is displayed, a polygon symbol becomes available in the &amp;ldquo;shape&amp;rdquo; control (see below). Select it to create the new location.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>map settings</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Select preferred map data from various providers. Some will provide additional layers (satellite view etc.) which you can toggle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;module-controls&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#module-controls&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;module controls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;dl&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;map source&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose the provider to source map information from.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;max polygon points&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/&#34;&gt;find location&lt;/a&gt; module doesn&amp;rsquo;t display polygons with more points than this for performance reasons. Usually a country polygon has between 50,000 and 150,000 points.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;show OSD&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Choose whether to display the OSD controls at the top-left of the center view.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;filtered images&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Check this box to display only the images from the current collection (those shown in the filmstrip) in the center view. Un-check the box to display all images in the current library, where those images have associated GPS data. You can also toggle this option by pressing Ctrl+S.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;max images&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The maximum number of thumbnails to display on the map.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;group size factor&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Increase or decrease the size of area that causes images to be grouped.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;min images per group&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;The minimum number of images that need to be placed in the same position in order to automatically create an image group for them.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dt&gt;thumbnail display&lt;/dt&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;Define what information to show on the map display&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;thumbnails&lt;/em&gt;: Display image thumbnails along with a counter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;count&lt;/em&gt;: Just display the number of images (to free space on the map). Hover over the number of images to show the corresponding thumbnail(s). A count-only marker behaves the same way as a normal image thumbnail, in terms of color coding, scrolling, drag and drop etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;none&lt;/em&gt;: Show nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;You can also cycle through these options by pressing Shift+S.&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dl&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
