<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>map on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/</link>
    <description>Recent content in map on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>find location</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/find-location/</guid>
      <description>Search for a location on the map. You must be connected to the internet to use this feature.&#xA;To use this module, type in a place name or address, press Enter and a list of results will be shown. Click on an item in the list and the map will zoom to that location. An outline covering that location or a pin pointing at the location will be displayed.&#xA;An outline (polygon) can be used to create a user location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>locations</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/locations/</guid>
      <description>Create areas or locations and organize them as hierarchical tags.&#xA;A location is shown as a shape on the map when selected. Initially each location is represented as a square or circle and can be changed to a rectangle or ellipse by adjusting the shape&amp;rsquo;s width and/or height.&#xA;A location can also be created from an OpenStreetMap region (city/country) polygon. To achieve this, first make sure the max polygon points parameter is large enough (some country polygons use more than 150,000 points).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>map settings</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/module-reference/utility-modules/map/map-settings/</guid>
      <description>Select preferred map data from various providers. Some will provide additional layers (satellite view etc.) which you can toggle.&#xA;🔗module controls map source Choose the provider to source map information from. max polygon points The find location module doesn&amp;rsquo;t display polygons with more points than this for performance reasons. Usually a country polygon has between 50,000 and 150,000 points. show OSD Choose whether to display the OSD controls at the top-left of the center view.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
