<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides &amp; Tutorials on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides &amp; Tutorials on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>developing monochrome images</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/monochrome/</guid>
      <description>Photography has a long history of producing monochrome images, and many still enjoy this aspect of photography. While there are some specialized/modified cameras with a truly monochrome sensor, most still use a regular camera to capture a color image and transform it into a monochrome image during post-processing.&#xA;There are two main approaches to this conversion:&#xA;A physical approach, where we attempt to simulate how a silver-based photographic film emulsion would react to the light captured at the scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>batch-editing images</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/batch-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/batch-editing/</guid>
      <description>Batch-editing is the process of developing images in a semantically-related series that are expected to have a consistent final look, often with the intent of publishing the images in catalogues, magazines or books. It can be a tedious, frustrating and unexciting task, so darktable includes functionality to help make it faster and more reliable.&#xA;🔗preparation 🔗shooting color checkers Shooting a color checker on-location can save a tremendous amount of time during batch post-processing of a series of images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>other resources</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/other-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/guides-tutorials/other-resources/</guid>
      <description>For help and support with using darktable you are encouraged to ask questions on the main discussion forums at discuss.pixls.us.&#xA;The official places to obtain information concerning darktable are the following:&#xA;darktable.org GitHub wiki The following articles provide some useful background information about darktable&amp;rsquo;s scene-referred workflow:&#xA;darktable 3.0 for dummies in 3 modules darktable 3.0 for dummies &amp;ndash; hardcore edition darktable 3.0: RGB or Lab? Which modules? Help! darktable&amp;rsquo;s filmic FAQ Introducing color calibration module The following resources can provide a deeper understanding of the functionality of some specific processing modules:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
