<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Special Topics on darktable 4.6 user manual</title>
    <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Special Topics on darktable 4.6 user manual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>memory &amp; performance tuning</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/mem-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/mem-performance/</guid>
      <description>🔗memory requirements Processing a Raw image in darktable requires a great deal of system memory. A simple calculation makes this clear: For a 20 megapixel image, darktable requires a 4x32-bit floating point cell to store each pixel, meaning that each full image of this size will require approximately 300MB of memory just to store the image data. In order to actually process this image through a given module, darktable needs at least two buffers (input and output) of this size, with more complex modules potentially requiring several additional buffers for intermediate data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>variables</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/variables/</guid>
      <description>darktable supports variable substitution in a number of modules and preference settings. For example:&#xA;Defining file names in the export module Displaying image information in the darkroom&amp;rsquo;s image information line Displaying image information in the lighttable&amp;rsquo;s overlays and tooltips (see preferences &amp;gt; lighttable) Placing text on an image in the watermark processing module 🔗available variables The following variables are available, though they may not all be applicable in every context:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>darktable&#39;s color pipeline</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/color-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Most image processing applications come from the 1990s and/or inherit a 1990s workflow. These applications processed images encoded with 8 bit unsigned integers because it was more memory- and computationally-efficient. However, due to the use of an integer format (which implies rounding errors) they had to apply a &amp;ldquo;gamma&amp;rdquo; (essentially a transfer function applying a power 1/2.2 or 1/2.4 to encode the RGB values) and increase the bit-depth in the low-lights in order to reduce rounding errors there (humans are very sensitive to low-light details).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>midi device support</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/midi-device-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/midi-device-support/</guid>
      <description>🔗introduction MIDI is a communication protocol used by many electronic musical instruments (&amp;ldquo;pianos&amp;rdquo;), digital audio studio equipment (&amp;ldquo;control surfaces&amp;rdquo;) and even dedicated &amp;ldquo;photo editing keyboards&amp;rdquo; like the Loupedeck/Loupedeck+ (but not their later products). Such devices commonly feature sets of keys/buttons and sometimes encoders (knobs/rotors) and faders (sliders). Buttons sometimes feature lights, which makes them ideal for toggling features in darktable, because the lights can reflect the current (on/off) status. Encoders and faders are ideal for use with on-screen sliders in processing modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contributing to dtdocs</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/contributing/</guid>
      <description>This page defines the style guide for dtdocs and information about how to contribute to the project.&#xA;It is included in the user manual so that you can see how the page is rendered as well as how it is written. Please go to GitHub to see the source for this page.&#xA;The manual structure and content have been carefully considered based on the following criteria:&#xA;The manual should be comprehensive &amp;ndash; it should describe all of the functionality available in darktable It should have a consistent and logical structure and every piece of functionality should have its own logical place within that structure It should be as long as necessary but as short as possible &amp;ndash; brevity is a must It should be objective Functionality should be explained once and only once (with the exception of the basic workflow guidelines in the overview section) Images should be included only where necessary to improve understanding of key principles and should not contain text unless it is unavoidable We are generally not interested in:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>translating dtdocs</title>
      <link>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/translating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://darktable-org.github.io/dtdocs/en/special-topics/translating/</guid>
      <description>Translation of the darktable documentation is done via our Weblate instance.&#xA;You can either use Weblate&amp;rsquo;s web UI to translate the documentation or download the translation from Weblate to your computer, edit it, and then upload the changes.&#xA;Please do all translation work through Weblate. We will not accept pull requests directly on github to update PO files.&#xA;🔗Making a new branch in git Make a new branch to work on it in git.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
